<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_9_3">
   <title>Creating a Schedule for a Model </title>
  <conbody>
    <p>You can schedule a model that you created for email distribution in PDF, CSV, or Hyperlink
      format. To do this, perform the following steps:</p><ol id="ol_sdn_gsk_3y">
        <li>Expand the nodes <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Data Design</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Analytics Workbench</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> in the left panel and select the <uicontrol>Models</uicontrol> tab. The
          Analytics Workbench is shown in the screenshot below.<image href="media/Image_371_1.png"
            placement="break" scale="50"/></li>
        <li>Select a model you want to schedule, click the checkbox besides the listed model. Click
            <image href="media/button_model_schedule.png" placement="inline" scale="60"/> (create a
          new schedule with this model).<p>The Anlytics Model Schedule Setting window opens.<image
              href="media/Image_371_2.png" placement="break" scale="40"/></p><note>The Selected
            model <uicontrol>Get Model COnfiguation</uicontrol> is already in the
              <uicontrol>Scheduled Models</uicontrol> list box.</note></li>
        <li>Set the following fields: <ul id="ul_yrc_xhl_3y">
            <li>Enter a name for the model's schedule in the <uicontrol>Schedule Name</uicontrol>
              textbox.</li>
            <li>To schedule the start date and time, to run the selected model, click in the
                <uicontrol>Start at</uicontrol> text box. Set the date and time in calendar popup.
              You can also manually enter or modify the values in the text box. The screenshot in
              step 2, shows the model is scheduled to start at 2 am on the 21st of December.</li>
            <li>To repeat the scheduled run once or more at intervals, specify the values in the
                <uicontrol>Repeat Every</uicontrol> fields: 1. specify the number of times in the
              textbox and 2. select the required interval from the dropdown list. The screenshot in
              step 2 shows that the model is scheduled to run at the scheduled time once every week
              for 4 weeks.</li>
            <li>Add more models to the schedule, from the <uicontrol>Select an Analytical Model to
                schedule</uicontrol> dropdown list, and click <uicontrol>Add Model</uicontrol>.</li>
            <li>To run the scheduled models at the same time, check the
                <uicontrol>Concurent</uicontrol> checkbox.</li>
            <li>To specify the input parameters for a scheduled models, select the required model in
              the <uicontrol>Specify the model input parameters, model: &lt;Scheduled Model
                Name></uicontrol> table. Each model has its own input parameter table.The following
              screenshot shows the table for the model <uicontrol>Schema Name
                Configuation</uicontrol>.<image href="media/Image_371_3.png" placement="break"
                scale="50" id="image_zrc_xhl_3y"/></li>
          </ul></li>
        <li>Click Save Schedule.</li>
      </ol>
  </conbody>
</concept>
