<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_10_6">
   <title>Adding/Modifying Groups in a Single/Multiple-AD Server Environment</title>
  <conbody>
    <p>This section describes how to add or modify groups. In a single/multiple-AD server
      environment, this applies to those users who belong to a specific group DN (Distinguished
      Name) of an AD server. Refer to the applicable section below, depending on whether you are
      adding or modifying a group in a single-AD server environment or a multiple one.</p>
    <p>
      <note>IMPORTANT: Before you proceed with group synchronization, be sure that each Analyzer
        user’s information is in synchronization with Active Directory. For more information on how
        to synchronize AD users with Analyzer, refer to the SenSage AP Administration Guide.</note>
    </p>
    <p>To add/modify a SenSage AP group in a Single-AD Server Environment:</p>
    <ol id="ol_bdw_5fs_zx">
      <li>Go to the Analyzer, select <menucascade><uicontrol>Administration</uicontrol><uicontrol>Groups</uicontrol></menucascade> from the dropdown submenu. The Manage
        Groups screen is displayed as shown in Figure 9-6. See step 2 or 3 depending on whether you
        are adding or modifying a group.<p>Figure 9-6: Manage Groups Screen</p><p><image href="./media/Image_398.png" placement="break" scale="50"/></p></li>
      <li>Click Add a Group button as shown in Figure 9-7 and enter a name for the new group. In the
         sample screen the name circulardev2 is entered.<p>Figure 9-7: Adding a New Group</p><p>
          <image href="./media/Image_399.jpg" id="image_ddw_5fs_zx" placement="break" scale="60"/>
        </p></li>
      <li>If this group requires synchronization from LDAP, select the Synchronize this group from
        LDAP checkbox and enter the following details:<p>a Select the AD server (displayed by IP
          address) from the dropdown list. b Specify the organization’s DN.</p><p>c Specify the
          group’s DN.</p></li>
      <li>If modifying a group, select the group that you want to change from the Select a Group
        dropdown. As shown in the example in Figure 9-8, when the Non_administrators group is
        selected, the information for the group is displayed. You can modify the group name and the
        LDAP configuration details.<p>Figure 9-8: Selecting a Group for Modification</p><p>
          <note>Make sure that if you modify the LDAP-related settings for a group with
            another LDAP server, upon synchronization, the existing users in the group will be
            removed and the new list of synced users is populated in the group.</note>
        </p></li>
      <li>Check users from the Not in this Group section that you want to be in the group. Click the
        right arrow to move them into the Members of this Group column.</li>
      <li>Click Save to save the changes.<p>Under Members of the this Group column, a list of users
          that is synchronized with the group is displayed.</p><p>
          <note>If the group DN of the AD server contains those user accounts which are listed
            under the Analyzer users list (upon synchronization), those user accounts are not
            populated in the synched group.</note>
        </p></li>
      <li>If desired, you can select what the roles will be for users in this group. For details on
        creating roles, see Adding and Modifying Roles.</li>
    </ol>
  </conbody>
</concept>
