<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_2_1">
   <title id="title_a2">What is SenSage AP Analyzer?</title>
   <conbody>
    <p>The SenSage AP Analyzer is comprehensive client tool for performing SenSage AP reporting,
      data modeling, and AP user administration. AP administrators assign privileges to Analyzer
      users to perform specific tasks:</p>
    <ul id="ul_k1d_cpl_zx">
      <li>
        <p>Users can view, create, run, schedule and edit their own reports, as well as set up and
          manage dashboards to display critical reporting data when and where it is needed. An
          import and export feature allows for reports and dashboards to be copied and shared among
          AP deployments.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>With the easy-to-use Report Wizard, users can configure both standard and
          Analyzer-featured reports for effective data presentation and create corresponding charts
          with a number of chart type options (such as area, bar, pie, etc.),</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>For more complex reporting, users can conveniently run and alter data models included in
          a SenSage AP installation using the Analyzer’s Analytics Workbench, an interactive and
          visual Data Modeling tool. The workbench includes a feature to manage models. For details
          on available sample models, including Insider Threat Detection, see the Analytics
          Guide.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>With the SQL Workbench, AP Analyzer provides users with a a SQL authoring tool to develop
          ad-hoc SQL queries and write SQL code using data from the EDW and other sources. Included
          in Workbench is the capability to bring in columns from tables, additional parameters, and
          edit a query as a report.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Users can view event data from information systems in AP Analyzer with ready-to-run AP
          Analytics reports and dashboards included in a SenSage AP installation. For details on
          available SenSage AP Analytics reports, see the Analytics Guide.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </conbody>
</concept>