<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_7_6">
   <title>Adding and Modifying Model Components to a New or Existing Model</title>
   <conbody>
    <ol id="ol_iym_vlr_zx">
      <li>Go to the Analyzer dashboard, select Data Design from the dropdown list, click Analytics
        Workbench, and click the Analytics tab.<p>The expands the Component listing showing all
          components in the system which you have permission to access. Component menu options are
          displayed across the top of the model listing. For details on these menu items, see
          Component Menu Options.</p><p>Figure 6-13: Components Listing</p><p>
          <image href="./media/Image_280.jpg" id="image_wwf_slr_zx" placement="break" scale="50"/>
        </p></li>
      <li>You can select a component for viewing in the following ways:<ol id="ol_bhy_ynr_zx">
          <li>To select a component, check the box to the left of the component name. To de-select,
            click the box again.</li>
          <li>To select all components, check the box at the top of all the checkboxes. To
            de-select, click the box again.</li>
          <li>To search for a component by name, type in the text box just below the component
              menu.<p>When you type the list of components will be filtered by the string that you
              type.</p></li>
          <li>To open and close each category of components, the triangle to the left of the
            category name. If you hold down the shift key and click, all the categories will be
            expanded or collapsed at once.</li>
        </ol><p>Figure 6-14: Component Listing with Model Canvas</p><p><image href="./media/Image_281.jpg" id="image_xwf_slr_zx" placement="break" scale="60"/></p><p>
          <note>When scrolling over components in categories, additional information will pop
            up.</note>
        </p><p>Figure 6-15: Information Popup on List Operations</p><p><image href="./media/Image_282.jpg" id="image_ywf_slr_zx" placement="break" scale="70"/></p></li>
      <li>To place components on the canvas, use your mouse to drag components from the mouse onto
        the canvas:<p>Figure 6-16: Dragging Component to Canvas</p><p><image href="./media/Image_283.jpg" id="image_axf_slr_zx" placement="break" scale="60"/></p><p>
          <note>After you have selected, a component, you will see the model canvas menu, allowing
            you to perform actions on the model currently on your canvas. For details on each option
            represented by an icon on the menu, see <xref
              href="c_sen_anal-7_6_5-Using-Model-Canvas-M_crm.xml"/>.</note>
        </p></li>
      <li>To connect components on the canvas, see “Connecting Components”, next</li>
    </ol>
  </conbody>
</concept>
