<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_5_11">
   <title>Integrating Data Models with the Report</title>
   <conbody>
    <p>Data models are used for processing data with a library of functions for augmentations,
      annotations, or manipulations. They are an alternative for downloading report results and
      importing the data into third party tools, such as Microsoft Excel, and processing the data
      there.</p>
    <p>In a data model the report data can be combined with any other data including data outside of
      databases. For instance you may have a report with the geo locations of IP addresses – a model
      could run through the location results and run a script to look at the historic temperature of
      each location at the time of the event on wunderground.com.</p>
    <p>To specify a data model for integration with your report:</p>
    <ol id="ol_lwd_4jq_zx">
      <li>In the Report Wizard, click the Analytics tab and then click the dropdown arrow under
        "Select an Analytics to process the report results" as shown in Figure 4-37.<p>A list of
          models that have input parameters appropriate for processing the result of your report is
          displayed. (So not all models in the library are shown on this dropdown.) The models
          displayed are generally with the input parameter of type "Table".</p><p>Figure 4-37:
          Specifying a Data Model for Report Integration</p><p><image href="./media/Image_192.png" placement="break" scale="50"/></p></li>
      <li>Click the specific model you would like to integrate with your report, then click
          Add.<p>Your report is now integrated with the model you selected. The screen below shows
          details of the model including the name, category, description, tags, and a complete list
          of the input and output parameters.</p><p>Figure 4-38: Details of Model for Report
          Integration</p><p>
          <image href="./media/Image_193.jpg" id="image_nwd_4jq_zx" placement="break" scale="60"/>
        </p></li>
      <li>When you are finished, click <b>Save </b>or choose one of the following Save Options: Save
        and close, Save run and retain (for report history), or Save and run once (no history).</li>
    </ol>
  </conbody>
</concept>
