<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_3_9">
   <title>Using Sort to Find a Specific Report Attribute</title>
   <conbody>
    <p>You can specify any of the label icons circled as shown in Figure 2-14 below to sort all
      reports by a specific report attribute. This allows you to find reports by attributes that
      cannot be filtered.</p>
    <fig><title>Sorting Report by Attributes</title><image href="./media/Image_099.jpg" height="212" width="533" id="image_jc5_xfm_zx"/></fig>
    <p>The following is a description (from left to right) of each available sort attribute:</p>
    <table id="table_mc5_xfm_zx">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1"/>
        <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2"/>
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry>Sort Attribute</entry>
            <entry>Description</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Report Type</entry>
            <entry>Either Wizard report or SQL Workbench Reports</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Report Name</entry>
            <entry>Name of the report</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Summary Reports</entry>
            <entry>Wizard reports that have aggregation are indicated with a checkmark.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Timestamp Reports</entry>
            <entry>Wizard reports that have the time range limit set to a field of type datetime.
              Hover the mouse over the clock icon to see the name of the field that is set in the
              report definition.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Field Value Filters</entry>
            <entry>An integer count of the number of fields used as filters in the report
              definition. If any of the filters are required for entry at report run time, the color
              of the integer is teal-green. Hovering the mouse over the clock icon will display the
              list of filters.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Analytics Models</entry>
            <entry>Reports that have models connected to this report that are automatically run
              after the report runs and which process the report results.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Chart Types</entry>
            <entry>Reports that have charts configured for the report. Hover the mouse over this
              icon to display the chart type.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Associated Reports</entry>
            <entry>An integer count of the number of drill-downs configured to associated reports
              for each report. Hover the mouse over the icon to display the names of the associated
              reports.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Last Updated</entry>
            <entry>The date and time the report was last updated.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>History Count</entry>
            <entry>The number of report versions within the report’s history retention
              period.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Space (MB)</entry>
            <entry>The size of the report in megabytes.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Tags</entry>
            <entry>Report tags (categories) under which the report is categorized.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </conbody>
</concept>
