<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_5_2">
   <title>Running a Report</title>
   <conbody>
    <p>To run a report:</p>
    <ol id="ol_n31_hpm_zx">
      <li>Go to the Analyzer dashboard, select Data Design from the dropdown list and click Reports.
        The Manage Report screen with the current listing of reports is displayed.</li>
      <li>First scroll or use filters to find the desired report. For details on finding reports,
        see Chapter 2: Viewing Reports. Then select the report:<p>a If you want to view a report’s
          last run, check the desired report, click the Run button, and from the dropdown list,
          select View Last Run. Otherwise, see Step 3.</p><note>The View Last Run option will access
          which ever is the latest report from the report’s history; the last report run can be
          either an ad hoc or scheduled report.</note><p>Figure 4-10: Selecting Report to
            Run</p><p><image href="./media/Image_149.png" placement="break" scale="45"/></p></li>
      <li>If selecting a report to run instead of viewing a last run of a report, choose one of the
        desired Run options described below: <p>
          <note>You may check only one report to run at one time; however, you can select other
            reports without waiting for the previous report to complete. If you have logged out of a
            session in which reports are running, they will continue to run, but will not be
            available for viewing in the Report Queue.</note>
        </p> Figure 4-11: Selecting Run Option <p><image href="./media/Image_150.png" scale="45" placement="break"/></p>
        <ol>
          <li>To run the report and retain a copy of the report for historical purposes, select Run
            and Retain. The report’s run history is retained up to a specified retention period that
            is set for the report (see “Setting Report Retention for Report History”, on page
            74).</li>
          <li>To run the report once and save it only for the duration of the session, select Run
            Once. After you end your session and log out, the report no longer exists in the system
            and no history of the run is recorded. <p>
              <image href="./media/Image_151.png" placement="break" scale="60"/>
            </p>
            <p>A sample report is displayed in the screenshot above. </p>
            <note>If your report does not display immediately, you can go to the Report Queue to see
              the status of your report run. For details see, “Viewing Report Run Status”, on page
              65.</note>
          </li>
          <li>To review the report history for the report you have just run, click the last icon on
            the toolbar as shown in pevious step (red-circle) to display the report with history of
            the the report runs. <p>Figure 4-13: Report Display with History</p><p>
              <image href="./media/Image_152.png" scale="50" placement="break"/>
            </p><p>
              <note>You can select the Information icon (in upper right of the screen, third icon
                from the right) to view the SQL code for the current result set which can provide
                you with information such as parameters used in the report.</note>
            </p>
          </li>
        </ol>
      </li>
    </ol>
    
  </conbody>
</concept>
