<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_2_6">
   <title>Configuring Time Zones</title>
   <conbody>
    <p>SenSage AP always converts timestamps in the logs that it receives to GMT (assuming a
      correctly configured Collector and a properly built Log Adapter). If a time zone has been
      specified in a log entry, AP will use the time zone value in the log entry as the basis for
      the conversion. Otherwise, if the log adapters are configured with a time zone, then AP
      converts those timestamps in the log entries. If the time zone information is not in the log
      entry nor in the adapter configuration, then timestamps in the logs are considered GMT.</p>
    <p>In Analyzer, users can customize what time zone is used when requesting reports as well as
      the time displayed in the reports. Time zone settings are specified in the Analyzer user
      profile settings screen as shown in Figure 1-3. Users are prompted to set the time zone they
      want to use on their first login to the Analyzer. By default all data is displayed in the
      user's local time zone. Users can also change time zone settings at any time later.</p>
    <p>Note that the time displayed in the reports is the adjusted time based on the time zone
      setting in the user profile of the user who ran the report; the user’s time zone is not
      derived from the time zone of the source system where the logs originated. When displaying,
      scheduling, or running reports, a date range option is available to enter date/time field
      entries. These fields are always assumed as GMT.</p>
    <p>
      <note>The clock on the client where the Analyzer web GUI is run should be synchronized and set
        to the same time zone as the Analyzer host (server). The Analyzer web GUI uses the client’s
        clock value in report headers in the GUI (that are not part of the actual report). If this
        clock is not synchronized with the Analyzer host, the time-range value in the report header
        in the GUI will not match the actual time-range in the report. Scheduled reports are run in
        the time zone of the Analyzer host.</note>
    </p>
  </conbody>
</concept>