<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_7_2_1">
   <title>Parts of a Model Component</title>
   <conbody>
    <p>Each component has its associated data types and input and output properties. Generally the
      value of input properties are set by the preceding component or by an input parameter. Output
      properties generally set the value of the next component or an output parameter.</p>
    <p>The model pictured in Figure 6-4 below has four components all with the same label “Analytic
      Component Sum”.</p>
    <p>Figure 6-4: Sample Model with Four Components</p>
    <p><image href="./media/Image_258.jpg" height="293" width="616" id="image_ozx_mbr_zx"/></p>
    <p>Following is an in depth description of each part of the model:</p>
    <table id="table_pzx_mbr_zx">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1"/>
        <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2"/>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Item</entry>
            <entry>Description</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Input parameters</entry>
            <entry>Data elements that are likely to change each time the model runs. These
              parameters can be set manually in the model or can be set (over-ridden) when the model
              is scheduled. The model in Figure 6-4 has two input parameters both labeled “Input
              List”.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Connections</entry>
            <entry>Lines that connect input and output parameters and properties. These lines define
              the logical flow of data through the model. There is no limit to the number of
              branches a model can have. If an input property has more than one connection numbers
              will appear that define the order of precedence for data coming in from the different
              connections. Connections are depicted in black in the model pictured in Figure
              6-4.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Data Type Identifiers</entry>
            <entry>
              <p>Used to identify the type of data that is applicable for any given input or output
                parameter or property. Types are represented with a different icon for each data
                type. See “Adding and Modifying Model Components to a New or Existing Model”, on
                page 119 for a a list of icons.</p>
              <p>For example in the model pictured above the calculator icon represents a single
                number and the calculator with multiple blue rectangles represents a list of
                numbers.</p>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Output Parameters</entry>
            <entry>The final result of the model execution. There can be any number of output
              parameters. The values of the output parameters are shown in a dialog box after model
              execution. If the output parameter is of type file. the file is generated on the
              Analyzer and a link is provided in the dialog box.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </conbody>
</concept>
