<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_3_7">
  <title id="title_a8">Using Filters to find a Report</title>
  <conbody>
    <p>As the number of reports you create increases, it will be useful to group the reports into
      different categories. You can create different category tags and apply them to the reports you
      create. This will help you manage your reports and find them more quickly. If a report falls
      into multiple categories, you can apply multiple category tags to the same report.</p>
    <p>You can use any of the following methods described below to narrow down and retrieve a
      specific report for viewing.</p>
    <ul id="ul_j43_c2m_zx">
      <li>
        <p>You can select a tag by clicking in the <i>-- filter by tags --</i> drop-down list and
          select a tag (category) under which the report is categorized. For example, in the
          screenshot below, selecting the tag <uicontrol>Administrative Reports</uicontrol> narrows
          the list of reports to those categorized as administrative reports.<fig
            id="fig_qfj_xgt_2y">
            <title>Figure 2-12-1</title>
            <image href="media/Image_095.png" placement="break" scale="40" id="image_jqx_ygt_2y"/>
          </fig></p>
        <p>
          <note>You can repeat the process to filter the list by multiple tags.</note>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Click in the <uicontrol>Report Name</uicontrol> filter and type part of a name of a
          report that you want to find. All the reports having the search text as part of their name
          are listed. For example, typing <uicontrol>schema</uicontrol> in the <b>Report Name</b>
          filter resulted in three reports in the list having <b>schema</b> in their names.<fig>
            <title>Figure 2-12-2</title>
            <image href="media/Image_095_1.png" placement="break" scale="40"/>
          </fig>Similarly, you can type the username of the owner in the Owner filter and get the
          list of reports owned by the user. The following filter shows the list of reports owned by
          the user <codeph>test1</codeph>. <fig>
            <title>Figure 2-12-3</title>
            <image href="media/Image_095_2.png" placement="break" scale="40"/>
          </fig></p>
        <note>The Report Name is case-sensitive. The list of reports will be filtered by reports
          with the same string in their name as what you typed.</note>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Filter for reports created in a specific date range using the <uicontrol>Last
            Updated</uicontrol> field. Click in the filter field to get the <uicontrol>Date Range
            Selection</uicontrol> dialog. Clicking the in the Start Data and End Date of the data
          range in the date calculator pop up dialog. You can also narrow the Hour, Minute, Second
          granularity as required. The screeshot below shows the date range selector with the date
          calculator. <fig>
            <title>Figure 2-12-4</title>
            <image href="media/Image_095_4.png" placement="break" scale="45"/>
          </fig></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p>You can add, remove, or modify the tag (category) list. To add a new tag, perform the
      following steps: 
    </p>
    <ol>
      <li>Click <image href="media/button_editTags.png" placement="inline" scale="60"/>. The
          <uicontrol>Edit Tags</uicontrol> dialog displays.<image href="media/Image_095_3.png"
          placement="break" scale="50"/></li>
      <li>Enter a new tag name in the <uicontrol>Add a tag</uicontrol> text box.</li>
      <li>Click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol>. The new tag appears in the list of tags.</li>
    </ol>
    <p>To edit an existing tag name, perform the following:</p><ul>
      <li>Click <image href="media/button_editTags.png" placement="inline" scale="60"/>. The
        <uicontrol>Edit Tags</uicontrol> dialog displays.</li>
      <li>Double click the tag name you want to edit. The tag is highlighted in the text box.<image
          href="media/Image_095_5.png" placement="break" scale="45"/></li>
      <li>Edit the tag name and press <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol>. The tag name gets updated.<note>Any reports tagged with the previous tag name are also updated and tagged with the new name.</note></li>
    </ul>
    <p>To delete a tag name, perform the following:</p><ul>
      <li>Click <image href="media/button_editTags.png" placement="inline" scale="60"/>. The
        <uicontrol>Edit Tags</uicontrol> dialog displays.</li>
      <li>Click <image href="media/button_deleteTags.png" placement="inline"/> in the
          <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> column of the tag name you want to delete.<p>If a report is already tagged with the tag you want to
          delete, the following message pops up: <image placement="break"
            href="media/button_deleteWarnTags.png" scale="50"/></p><p>If the tag
          name is not in use, it is deleted from the list.</p></li>
    </ul>
  </conbody>
</concept>
