<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_5_10">
   <title>Specifying Data Filters for the Report</title>
   <conbody>
    
      <p>The data filter features provided for your report let you:</p>
      <ul id="ul_hfb_tgq_zx">
          <li>
            <p>Define complex data filters for any given field; these filters include the following:
              =, !=, &lt;, &lt;=,</p>
            <p>> >=, is between, is not between, contains, does not contain, empty, is not empty,
              starts with and ends with.</p>
            <p>Depending on the datatype for a column in your report, applicable filter options are
              presented for your selection. Boxes to enter your filter values also inform you
              whether an entry is required or optional.</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>Create filters in the report for fields not displayed in the report.</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>Set options to limit rows returned in a result set and retention period for your
              report’s history. </p>
          </li>
        </ul>
    
    <p>To specify data filters for your report:</p>
    <ol id="ol_ifb_tgq_zx">
      <li>Click the Data Filters tab in the Report Wizard.</li>
      <li>If desired, provide entries for the following options:<ol><li>To set a limit for the number of rows returned in the result set, check the box: "Limit the
            number of results returned to":, which enables your configurable parameter to the number specified.<p>
              <note>By default, the limit is 2500, however, you can change this limit to any
                positive integer. Generally, this setting is used for the "Top 100" type reports
                noted in the Analytics Guide.</note>
            </p></li><li>Change the retention period for retaining the report’s history. The default is seven
              days.<p>Figure 4-33: Limiting Number of Results</p><p><image href="./media/Image_187.png" placement="break" scale="50"/></p></li></ol></li>
      <li>If desired, to filter the report by fields not displayed in the report (without
        corresponding rows on the Report Fields tab), click the Add a column button in the upper
        right corner.<p>A dialog box similar to the initial field selector dialog box (when you
          first defined the report) is displayed listing additional fields from the same source
          table.</p><p>Figure 4-34: Filtering Report with Undisplayed Fields</p><p><image href="./media/Image_188.png" placement="break" scale="50"/></p></li>
      <li>To set the filter for any given field, click the dropdown arrow on the row corresponding
        to the field you want to filter by. The options for filtering type for that field are
          displayed.<p>Figure 4-35: Filtering Type Options</p><p><image href="./media/Image_189.jpg" placement="break" scale="70"/></p><p>After you select the filter type,
          entry boxes appropriate for that type of filter are displayed on the right. For details on
          "prompt user" and "choose from..." filter types, see <xref
            href="c_sen_anal-5_9-Providing-Interactiv_crm.xml"/>.</p><p><image
            href="./media/Image_190.jpg" placement="break" scale="70"/></p></li>
      <li>Enter valid report values in these filter type entry boxes. Figure 4-36: Entering Values
        for Filter Type Options</li>
      <li>When you are finished, click <b>Save </b>or choose one of the following Save Options: Save
        and close, Save run and retain (for report history), or Save and run once (no history).</li>
    </ol>
  </conbody>
</concept>
