<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_6_3">
   <title>Creating or Modifying an Area Chart</title>
   <conbody>
    <p>An Area Chart consists of an X-axis and a Y-axis. To create or edit an Area Chart:</p>
    <ol id="ol_aps_gwq_zx">
      <li>Access the area chart settings screen (for instructions see <xref
          href="c_sen_anal-6_1-Creating-a-Chart_crm.xml"/> or <xref
          href="c_sen_anal-6_2-Editing-a-Chart---TH_crm.xml"/>.</li>
      <li>If desired, enter (in this optional field) a title for the chart for descriptive purposes
        only.</li>
      <li>Specify the datatype for the Y-axis (the vertical dimension) under the dropdown box
        labelled "Plot values from the field:" shown in Figure 5-6.<p>
          <note>It is generally good practice to use a field with a numeric datatype for the Y-axis.
            If you select a string datatype the system will automatically add the count()
            aggregation function to determine the vertical height of elements in the chart, this can
            lead to unexpected results.</note>
        </p><p>Figure 5-6: Defining Area Chart</p><p>
          <image href="./media/Image_217.jpg" id="image_bps_gwq_zx" placement="break" scale="70"/>
        </p></li>
      <li>Specify the datatype for the X-axis (the horizontal dimension of the chart) under the
        dropdown box labelled "Use the following field for the X-axis of the graph:" shown in Figure
        5-6. The values in this field will be listed as labels in the chart itself. You can use
        fields of either string or number datatypes for the Y-axis.</li>
      <li>Click Save. <p>Figure 5-7 shows the results of the configuration implemented so far. Note
          the name of the Y- axis field shows in the "Key" box on the right and values from the
          field "Protocol" show as labels for each value across the bottom of the
          report.</p><p>Figure 5-7: Area Chart Configuration</p><p><image
            href="./media/Image_219.jpg" height="300" width="611" id="image_dps_gwq_zx"/></p></li>
      <li>Optionally, to display more information than the number in the Y-axis field, you can
        select another field for break down; to do this, select the second field in the box
        <codeph>--select the corresponding value label field (if any) --</codeph> as shown in Figure 5-8 in which
        <codeph>Firewall Device</codeph> is chosen.<p>Note that the box for the second field is displayed whenever
          a field of numeric datatype is used.</p><p>Figure 5-8: Display "Firewall Device" in "Y"
          Axis Field of Area Chart</p><p><image href="./media/Image_220.jpg" height="303"
            width="596" id="image_eps_gwq_zx"/></p></li>
      <li>Click Save. DOES CLICKING SAVE DISPLAY THE CHART?<p>At this point multiple “areas” are
          displayed on the chart as shown in Figure 5-9. Note the new listing of labels in the Key
          box on the right.</p> Figure 5-9: Labels in the Areas Chart <p><image
            href="./media/Image_222.jpg" height="344" width="595" id="image_gps_gwq_zx"/></p></li>
      <li>Click the gear icon and select Edit to display the chart settings screen for the
          chart.<p>Figure 5-10: Area Chart Settings Screen</p><p><image href="./media/Image_224.jpg"
            height="269" width="610" id="image_ips_gwq_zx"/></p><note>
          <p>Note the following additional viewing options at the bottom of the chart settings
            screen: Orientation, Stacking, and Display</p>
          <p>The “Graph style:” allows you to removing the shading below the line, converting an
            Area Chart into a Line Chart.</p>
          <draft-comment author="Hemraj"> WHERE IS THE GRAPH SYTLE?????</draft-comment>
          <p><ph id="a86">The “Display:” box allows you to show or hide the labels on each axis.
                <draft-comment author="Hemraj">DO YOU MEAN CHECKING THE DATA LABELS
                BOX?</draft-comment></ph></p>
        </note></li>
    </ol>
    

  </conbody>
</concept>
