<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_9_2">
   <title>Creating a Report Schedule</title>
   <conbody>
    <p>To create a new schedule for a report:</p>
    
    <ol id="ol_ory_jzr_zx">
      <li>After you have accessed the Scheduler in the Analyzer menu, click the Schedules sub-menu,
        and click the Add a schedule button as shown below.<p>Figure 8-2: Adding a
            Schedule</p><p><image href="./media/Image_365.jpg" placement="break" scale="50"/></p><p>The Reporting Schedule Settings screen is displayed to
          enter your report scheduling information for the new schedule.</p></li>
      <li>Provide a name for your schedule as shown below. Note in order to save the schedule, you
        must specify a schedule name.<p>Figure 8-3: Report Schedules Settings Screen</p><p><image href="./media/Image_366.png" placement="break" scale="50"/></p></li>
      <li>Click the triangle in the box labeled, "Select a Report to add to this schedule" to
        display the dropdown list of reports that you have permission to access.<p>
          <note>You can type part of the report name to filter the list of reports that have
            the name matching the string you typed.</note>
        </p><p><image href="./media/Image_367.png" placement="break" scale="50"/></p></li>
      <li>From the dropdown list, click the desired report. Figure 8-4: Selecting Report to Add to
          Schedule<p>If the report was defined with parameters, they will appear to the right of the
          report dropdown list.</p></li>
      <li>Enter the desired parameters and any parameters required for the report.<note>If the
          report definition has any parameters configured as "required," then a checkbox is
          displayed in the "Req’d" column and you must provide values for those parameters before
          saving the schedule.</note><p>Figure 8-5: Selecting Parameters for the Report</p><p><image href="./media/Image_368.png" placement="break" scale="40"/></p><p>The
          icon with the number of parameters in red will be displayed in the list of reports to be
          run with the schedule. You will also be alerted in "red" text if you partially complete
          any parameter such as selecting the Operator, but not filling in a parameter value for
          it.</p></li>
      <li>Select any additional reports (no limit) you want to schedule. When you click the name of
        each selected report, the parameter configuration options for that report is
          displayed.<p>Figure 8-6: Selecting Additional Reports to Schedule</p><p><image href="./media/Image_369.png" placement="break" scale="50"/></p></li>
      <li>To specify the run time for these reports, enter the values for the fields labeled Start
        at: and Repeat every: For example, the report shown below will run everyday at 2:00 AM GMT.
        This setting is independent of the time range data in the report configured on the Next tab.
          <p>Figure 8-7: Sample Report Schedule</p><p><image href="./media/Image_371.png" scale="50" placement="break"/></p><p>
          <note>If you use the manual picker to schedule the time and provide a time in the
            past, your job will not run until the next scheduled time. Providing a time in the past
            is the same as scheduling the first run in the future.</note>
        </p><p>If you want to schedule a report to run at 1 am every Monday, then schedule the
          report to start the next Monday. If you want the report to run “now”, then select “now”,
          let the report run, and then update the schedule for next Monday. This sets the schedule
          for the next run at your desired day and time.</p>
      </li>
    </ol>

  </conbody>
</concept>
