<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_5_5">
   <title>Joining Multiple Tables in the Report</title>
   <conbody>
    <p>You can have an existing table in your report joined by one or more specified tables from
      your data source.To add tables to your report:</p>
    <ol id="ol_d54_gdq_zx">
      <li>Perform step a or b to select table(s) for the join:
      <ol>
        <li>If you are not certain which table(s) to join or you want to use a field for the join
            that you have not already selected, click the Add a table button. Go to Step 2.</li><li>If you do know which field you want to use to join the tables and you have selected that table
            (so that it is showing in the field list), click the ‘link’ icon to the right of the
            field name. This will save a step in the next dialog box. Go to Step 3. <p>Figure 4-17:
              Selecting Table/Field to Join</p><p><image href="./media/Image_164.png" placement="break" scale="50"/></p></li>
      </ol>
      </li>
      <li>If you clicked the Add a table button, you first need to select the columns that you want
        to use to join the tables on the left side of the dialog box. You can filter to specific
        fields quickly by typing in the "column name filter" box.<p>Figure 4-18: Select the First
          Column(s) for Join</p><p><image href="./media/Image_165.jpg" height="291" width="575"
            id="image_f54_gdq_zx"/></p></li>
      <li>After the column(s) is selected, choose the second column you want to use. Click the arrow
        next to a schema to expand the list of tables in that schema. Then click the arrow next to
        the table to expand the list of columns in that table. To quickly find specific tables or
        columns, type part of the name in the "table name filter" or "column name filter" boxes respectively.<p>
          <note>The second column(s) can be from any table in any namespace; however, it must
            be of the same datatype as the first field.</note>
        </p><p><image href="./media/Image_166.png" placement="break" scale="45"/></p></li>
      <li>Click the column name(s) that you want to use and then click Done. <p>Figure 4-19: Second
          Column(s) for Join<image id="image_c21_jyh_3y"/></p><p>The relationship that you just
          defined is now applied in a new grid below the fields grid. You can now add more
          conditions for the join to the same table or add more joins to other tables.</p><p>
          <note>The second column from the new table is not listed in the original fields grid. To
            add columns from the second table for viewing in the report, click the Add fields
            button. Also note that a “left join” is performed on joined tables and currently no
            options are provided to perform a "center" or "right join."</note>
        </p><p>Figure 4-20: Add Fields from Second Table for Display</p><p><image href="./media/Image_167.png" placement="break" scale="50"/></p><p>As
          you select each new field that you want to appear in the report, the field will move from
          the left side to the right side of the dialog box.</p></li>
      <li>When finished selecting your fields, click Select. <p>Figure 4-21: Select Columns to Add
          to Report</p><image href="./media/Image_168.png" placement="break" scale="50"/><p>After
          you have selected your additional fields, all fields are displayed in one grid as shown in
          Figure 4-22. The small gray text under each field shows the name of the table. To
          avoid</p><p>confusion, you can rename the headers in fields that may have an identical
          name in both tables.</p></li>
      <li>When you are finished, click <b>Save </b>or choose one of the following Save Options: Save
        and close, Save run and retain (for report history), or Save and run once (no history).
          <p>Figure 4-22: Completed Join Display</p><p><image href="./media/Image_169.png" placement="break" scale="50"/></p>
      </li>
    </ol>

  </conbody>
</concept>
