<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_7_3_1">
   <title>Adding and Modifying Model Input and Output Parameters</title>
   <conbody>
    
      <p>Models can accept input parameters and can return results. The count of input and output
        parameters inside a function will be equal to this count when you drop a model inside
        another model. You can see the equality of parameters on the slide with red, green, blue and
        pink lines. Count of input and output parameters is unlimited. DON’T SEE THIS ON THE
          SLIDE.</p>
     <p>On a model component, when you want to add either an input or output
          parameter:</p><ol id="ol_pmv_vdr_zx">
          <li>Right-click the "input" or "result" icon on a model.</li>
          <li>Select "Make model input".<p>A purple model input icon is displayed to enter your
              input. Provide the name of your input or output parameter. The system provides a
              datatype identifier to indentify the type of data that is applicable for any given
              input or output parameter or property. IS AN ERROR MESSAGE DISPLAYED IF THE DATATYPE
              IS INCORRECT?</p><p>
              <note>Types are represented with a different icon for each data type. Depending
                on the datatype of your parameter, you will see one of the following icon types
                beside your parameter entry as noted in Figure 6-7.</note>
            </p><p>Figure 6-7: Icon Types for Parameters</p><p><image href="./media/Image_267.jpg"
                height="260" width="464" id="image_qmv_vdr_zx"/></p><p>Figure 6-8 below displays the
              icons for the following datatypes: the green calculator icon represents an integer,
              the grey calculator icon represents a number, the text icon represents a text, the
              calendar icon represents a timestamp.</p><p>Figure 6-8: Example of Icon Types in a
              Component</p><p><image href="./media/Image_268.jpg" height="231" width="431"
                id="image_rmv_vdr_zx"/></p></li>
          <li>If you have a list of parameter values that are required with your Analytic Component,
            you will be prompted to provide the value in a text. A list is a data structure
            consisting of a collection of elements of the same data type. CHECK THIS. After you
            click Save, a blue rectangular box appears in the datatype icon to denote that more than
            one parameter value is assigned.<p>Figure 6-9 provides an example of three components
              that accept a list of values. Concatenate Strings accepts a list of text values and
              returns a concatenated text in a single text variable.</p><p>Standard Deviation
              accepts a list of numbers and returns a standard deviation value of the input numbers.
              Split String component accepts Input and Delimiter values and returns a list of text
              values.</p><p>Figure 6-9: Example of Input Parameter List</p><p><image
                href="./media/Image_269.jpg" height="275" width="419" id="image_smv_vdr_zx"
            /></p></li>
          <li>Click Save.<note>The count of input and output parameters inside a function will be
          equal to this count when you drop this model inside another model. You can see the
          equality of parameters on the slide with red, green, blue and pink lines. Count of input
          and output parameters is unlimited.</note></li>
        </ol>
    
    <p>To modify either an input or output parameter:</p>
    <ol id="ol_umv_vdr_zx">
      <li>Right-click the "input" or "result" icon on a model.</li>
      <li>Click the option corresponding to what you want to modify as noted below (see Figure 6-10
        and Figure 6-11).<ul id="ul_vmv_vdr_zx">
          <li>
            <p>To rename a parameter, click "Rename Parameter" in the popup menu. Change the name of
              the parameter in the text box and click the Save to right of the text box.</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>To assign a default value to an input parameter, allowing this value for use if the
              parameter for this model is not assigned, click "Set Parameter Value" in the popup
              menu. Change the value in the text box and click Save to the right of the text
              box.</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>To delete a parameter, click "Delete" in the popup menu. Click Save. CHECK THIS TO
              SEE IF SAVE APPEARS</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>To copy a parameter, click "Copy" in the popup menu. Then go to the model component
              where you we want to copy the parameter. Click the "input" or "result" icon and paste
              the parameter name in text box.</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>To specify a bounded/unbounded state for the parameter, right-click "Make Bounded
              (List)" or "Make Unbounded (List)" Click Save. NEED TO CHECK THIS.</p>
          </li>
        </ul></li>
    </ol>
    <p>Figure 6-10: Setting Model Input Parameter</p>
    <p><image href="./media/Image_271.jpg" height="138" width="599" id="image_wmv_vdr_zx"/></p>
    <p>Figure 6-11: Setting Model Output Parameter</p>
    <p><image href="./media/Image_272.jpg" height="144" width="570" id="image_xmv_vdr_zx"/></p>
  </conbody>
</concept>
