<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="t_sen_anal-7_3-Creating-and-Editing_crm">
    <title></title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p></p>
            <p>To create or edit a data model, perform the following tasks:</p>
            <p>1 Access the Analytics Model Information screen. See step a or b depending on whether
                you are creating a model or editing one.</p>
            <p>a If creating a new model, go to the Analyzer dashboard, select Data Design from the
                dropdown list and click Analytics Workbench, and Analytics. Go to step 2.</p>
            <p>b If editing a model, go to the Analyzer dashboard, select Data Design from the
                dropdown list and click Analytics Workbench, and Models. Find the model you want to
                edit. See Viewing a Model for methods to access a model and then click the
                Information icon next to the Save button.</p>
            <p><image href="Image_260.png" height="32" width="3" id="image_q12_tcr_zx"/></p>
            <p>A sample model canvas is displayed. Note that the libraries menus is collapsed, so
                only the canvas is displayed without the libraries palette.</p>
            <p>Figure 6-5: Sample Model Canvas</p>
            <p><image href="Image_261.jpg" height="529" width="601" id="image_r12_tcr_zx"/></p>
            <p><image href="Image_262.png" height="48" width="3" id="image_s12_tcr_zx"/></p>
            <p>2 When you see the Analytics Model information screen, as shown below, define or edit
                existing model information (Name, Category, Description, Tags, and Input/Output)
                parameters by filling or revising the information screen as shown Figure 6-6
                below.</p>
            <p>NOTE: Category is required for selection whether creating a new model or editing an
                existing one.</p>
            <p>Figure 6-6: Analytics Model Information Screen</p>
            <p><image href="Image_263.jpg" height="524" width="581" id="image_t12_tcr_zx"/></p>
            <ol id="ol_u12_tcr_zx">
                <li>
                    <p>Click Save when you have finished.</p>
                    <p>If the current model wasn’t previously saved, the system saves it as a new
                        model and displays the model canvas.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Create the model on the canvas or edit a model’s canvas:</p>
                    <p>a If creating a new model or editing an existing one, use the model library
                        to create the new/ revised components for the model on the model canvas. For
                        details on using the "model library" and adding/revising model components,
                        see “Adding and Modifying Model Components to a New or Existing Model”, on
                        page 119. See the icons used to draw models on the canvas on page 125.</p>
                    <p>b If adding a model component to a new or existing model, see page 119 for
                        details. To edit model components, see step d.</p>
                    <p>c If adding a model to embed in your existing model, access the model library
                        to add the embedded model. For details, see “Nesting (embedding) a Model
                        into an Existing Model”, on page 118.</p>
                    <p><image href="Image_264.png" height="32" width="3" id="image_v12_tcr_zx"/></p>
                    <p>d If editing a model component input or output parameter, see “Adding and
                        Modifying Model Input and Output Parameters”, next.</p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd></cmd>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
