<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_3_9_2_3">
   <title>Copying Files and Directories to Each Host (clsync)</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>This section describes the clsync utility, which synchronizes local files and
              directories with files and directories on specified remote hosts.</p>
      <ul id="ul_zz3_tcl_vx">
         <li>
            <p>For files, ensures that the file is replicated in the same location on each host.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p>For directories, this utility recursively synchronizes the contents of the directory.
          This utility uses the <codeph>rsync</codeph> program.</p>
         </li>
      </ul>
      <p>This section contains the following topics:<ul id="ul_npz_xcl_vx">
            <li><xref href="#topic_3_9_2_3/3923_1"/></li>
            <li><xref href="#topic_3_9_2_3/3923_2"/></li>
            <li><xref href="#topic_3_9_2_3/3923_3"/></li>
            <li><xref href="#topic_3_9_2_3/3923_4"/></li>
         </ul></p>
      <section id="3923_1">
         <title>SYNOPSIS</title>
         <p>
            <codeph>clsync [<i>general_options</i>] [<i>specific_options</i>] &lt;<i>source_item</i>&gt;
            [&lt;<i>source_item</i>&gt; […]]</codeph>
         </p>
      </section>
      <section id="3923_2">
         <title>ARGUMENTS</title>
         <p>
            <codeph>&lt;<i>source_item</i>&gt;</codeph>
         </p>
         <p>You must specify at least one source item. Additional source items are optional. Separate
        multiple items with spaces. You can specify files, directories, or combinations of both, as
        the following three examples show:</p>
         <codeblock xml:space="preserve">clsync file1 tmp/file2.txt file3 clsync dir1 dir2
clsync file1 tmp/file2.txt dir1</codeblock>
         <p>If you specify a path without a leading slash (/), the utility resolves the path from the
        current directory. The utility synchronizes the local files and directories with those in
        the same current directory on the other hosts in the cluster. If the corresponding files are
        in a different location on the other hosts, use the --target-dir option to specify the
        alternate, remote location.</p>
      </section>
      <section id="3923_3">
         <title>OPTIONS</title>
         <p>
            <codeph>[general_options]</codeph>
         </p>
         <p>See <xref href="c_admin_guide-3_9_1-General-Syntax-for-U_snsg.xml#topic_3_9_1"/>.</p>
         <p>
            <codeph>[specific_options]</codeph>
         </p>
         <parml>
            <plentry>
               <pt>
                  <codeph>--hosts</codeph>
               </pt>
               <pd>Executes command on hosts specified in the list; defaults to localhost</pd>
            </plentry>
         </parml>
         <parml>
            <plentry>
               <pt>
                  <codeph>--sls-instance</codeph>
               </pt>
               <pd>Executes command on every host on which the specified instance is running; value can also be set
            through the <codeph>SLS_INSTANCE</codeph> environment variable.</pd>
            </plentry>
         </parml>
         <parml>
            <plentry>
               <pt>
                  <codeph>--target-dir</codeph>
               </pt>
               <pd>The target directory on remote hosts where the files and directories to be synchronized are
            located. Use this option if the location of files to synchronize are in different
            locations on the remote hosts than on the local host. If the remote locations on remote
            hosts differ by host, use the <codeph>&lt;host&gt;:&lt;path&gt;</codeph> syntax for specifying
            hosts with the <codeph>--hosts</codeph> option described above.</pd>
            </plentry>
         </parml>
         <parml>
            <plentry>
               <pt>
                  <codeph>--exclude</codeph>
               </pt>
               <pd>When it examines directories for files to synchronize, the clsync utility ignores
                  files and directories with base names that match the specified pattern. Separate
                  multiple patterns with spaces or use multiple <codeph>--exclude</codeph> options.
                  Enclose the patterns within single quotes, for example:
                  <codeblock>clsync --exclude=’**/dsroot/**’ /opt/sensage/etc</codeblock></pd>
            </plentry>
         </parml>
         <parml>
            <plentry>
               <pt>
                  <codeph>--include</codeph>
               </pt>
               <pd>Use the --include option to selectively override excluded items. When it ignores files and
            directories because of the <codeph>--exclude</codeph> option, the
              <codeph>clsync</codeph> utility does not ignore files and directories with base names
            that match the pattern specified for <codeph>--include</codeph>. Separate multiple
            patterns with spaces or use multiple <codeph>--include</codeph> options. Enclose the
            patterns within single quotes, for example: clsync --exclude=’**/dsroot/**’
            --include=’*.xml’ /opt/sensage/etc</pd>
            </plentry>
         </parml>
      </section>
      <section id="3923_4">
         <title>RETURNS</title>
         <p>A report of what <codeph>clsync</codeph> did, organized by host.</p>
      </section>
      <section id="3923_5">
         <title>EXAMPLE</title>
         <p>Following is an example of the <codeph>clsync</codeph> command executed on a two-node
            cluster: dev-01,dev-02 in this example, a file is missing on dev-02. The
               <codeph>clsync</codeph> command identifies the missing file and copies it from dev-01
            to dev-02, bringing the two nodes back in sync.</p>
         <p> </p>
         <codeblock xml:space="preserve">[root@dev-01 latest]# clsync --hosts=dev-01,dev-02 /opt/sensage/sql/
clsync - clsetup-4.7.0, change #73647;

Initializing (ssh) root@dev-01.sensage.com
Initializing (ssh) root@dev-02.sensage.com
Pending: 0 Lagging: - last file copied: .../oae/sls_name.sql
Done

====[dev-01.sensage.com]====
/opt/sensage/sql/ -> &lt;same place>: no files copied.
No files copied.

====[dev-02.sensage.com]====
/opt/sensage/sql/oae/sls_name.sql -> &lt;same place>
Total number of files copied: 1

[root@dev-01 latest]#</codeblock>
      </section>
   </conbody>
</concept>