<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_4_2_2">
   <title>Description</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>The <codeph>atquery</codeph> utility processes:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>Data Manipulation Language (DML) statements, which query (SELECT) data in a table and
      retire (RETIRE) data from a table in an EDW instance. <p>For more information, see Overview of AP SQL SELECT Statements in “SenSage AP SQL” of the
        <cite>Collector Guide</cite> and <xref href="c_admin_guide-4_5-Retiring-Data_snsg.xml#topic_4_5"/>.</p>
         </li>
         <li>Data Definition Language (DDL) statements, which create tables, column filters, and views
      within an EDW instance.<p>For more information on the DDL statements that the atquery command can process, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-5_3-Defining-Data-Object_snsg.xml#topic_5_3"/>.</p>
         </li>
      </ul>
      <p>The <codeph>atquery</codeph> utility supports processing multiple SQL files at once. If you specify the names
      of SQL files on the command line, they are processed in the order specified. When specifying
      multiple files, separate each name with a space.</p>
      <p>After processing its arguments and checking the SQL files for obvious errors, the querying
      process proceeds as follows. For each SQL file, <codeph>atquery</codeph>:</p>
      <ol>
         <li>Connects to the specified host and port.</li>
         <li>Sends the SQL file, wrapped as an XML-RPC "message" (also known as XML data).</li>
         <li>Listens for errors, progress messages, and result records.</li>
         <li>On the server, parses the query, sends new queries to each of the hosts in the instance, and
        combines the results to form the final result.<note>If the <codeph>Primary</codeph> directory (which contains
          the primary copy of log data) is unavailable, the EDW uses the <codeph>Secondary</codeph> directory (which
          contains the backup copy of log data). If both of these directories are unavailable, the
          query fails. If the query uses the Secondary directory, processing is slower than when it
          uses the <codeph>Primary</codeph>. For more information about these directories, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-2_2-EDW-Architecture_snsg.xml#topic_2_2"/>.</note>
         </li>
      </ol>
      <section>
         <title>INTERNATIONAL SUPPORT FOR QUERYING DATA</title>
         <p>The character encoding of <i>
               <filepath>&lt;file_name&gt;.sql</filepath>
            </i> must be UTF-8.
        ASCII character encoding is a proper subset of UTF-8 character encoding.</p>
         <p>For more information on character encoding, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-5_7_1-International-Suppor_snsg.xml#topic_5_7_1"/>.</p>
      </section>
   </conbody>
</concept>