<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
         id="topic_10_2_2_2">
   <title>Specifying Data Retention in Centera NSAs</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>You can configure Centera NSAs with a retention period. Setting a retention period requires
      SenSage AP to retain references to the archived data in the EDW and the data itself on the
      Centera unit until the retention period passes and you retire the data from the EDW. Only
      after the retention period has passed can you retire data from the EDW and the NLS device. You
      must run atquery with the retire command on the EDW table to remove the archived data from the
      EDW and the Centera unit. For more information, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-4_5-Retiring-Data_snsg.xml#topic_4_5"/>.</p>
      <p>
         <note>When you retire archived data that is not under retention, SenSage AP removes the
        references to the data from the EDW and removes the data itself from the Centera
        unit.</note>
      </p>
      <p>There are two ways to specify the retention period: retentionPeriod and retentionClass. Each
      of these is preceded by a pipe symbol (|).</p>
      <ul id="ul_vgr_43q_wx">
         <li>retentionPeriod—basic
          syntax<codeblock xml:space="preserve">|retentionPeriod=&lt;<i>num_seconds</i>&gt;</codeblock>Syntax for specifying
          the retention period for a Centera
              unit:<codeblock xml:space="preserve">"centera://&lt;<i>Host_Identifier&gt;</i>|retentionPeriod=&lt;<i>num_seconds</i>&gt;"</codeblock>
            <p>
               <b>Examples</b>
               <codeblock xml:space="preserve">atmanage "edw01:8072,edw02:8072,edw03:8072" --user=administrator \
--password=changeme \
setnsi "centera://centera1.cascommunity.org|retentionPeriod=31536000"</codeblock>
               <codeblock xml:space="preserve">atmanage "edw01:8072,edw02:8072,edw03:8072" --user=administrator \
--password=changeme \
setnsi "centera://10.2.3.4,10.006.07.8|retentionPeriod=31536000"</codeblock>
            </p>
            <note>
               <ul id="ul_k14_hjq_wx">
                  <li>When you specify a retention period of some specific number of seconds, you ensure
                that data archived with that NSI is under a fixed length of retention. The data will
                be available for deletion when that number of seconds has passed.</li>
                  <li>After data has been archived with a retention period of a fixed number of seconds,
                the retention period cannot be changed on the Centera. You can only change the
                retention period by deleting and re- defining the target. Use
                  <codeph>deletensi</codeph> to delete the existing one and <codeph>setnsi</codeph>
                to define a new one. For more information, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-10_2_1-Defining-and-Managin_snsg.xml#topic_10_2_1"/>.</li>
                  <li>The number of seconds you specify will be a very large number. For example, 86400
                seconds represent a single day.</li>
               </ul>
            </note>
         </li>
         <li>retentionClass—basic
            syntax<codeblock xml:space="preserve">|retentionClass=&lt;<i>class_name</i>&gt;</codeblock>
            <p>Syntax for
            specifying a retention class for a Centera
            unit:<codeblock xml:space="preserve">"centera://&lt;<i>Host_Identifier&gt;</i>]<b>|retentionClass=&lt;</b><i><b>class_name</b></i><b>&gt;</b>"</codeblock>
            </p>
            <p>
               <b>Examples</b>
               <codeblock xml:space="preserve">atmanage "edw01:8072,edw02:8072,edw03:8072" --user=administrator \
--password=changeme \
setnsi "centera://centera1.cascommunity.org|retentionClass=IgniteTech"</codeblock>
               <codeblock xml:space="preserve">atmanage "edw01:8072,edw02:8072,edw03:8072" --user=administrator \
--password=changeme \
setnsi "centera://10.2.3.4,10.006.07.8|retentionClass=IgniteTech"</codeblock>
            </p>
         </li>
      </ul>
      <section>
         <title>Usage</title>
         <ul>
            <li>The value you specify for <codeph>&lt;<i>class_name</i>&gt;</codeph> is provided by a Centera
          administrator. The class name specifies the retention period as defined by the
          administrator.</li>
            <li>When you specify a retention class on the Centera, the archived data is associated with a
    named retention class on the device. Depending on the model of the Centera unit (as
    illustrated in the table below), a retention class can be modified to represent a longer or
    shorter period of time. The changes are retroactive, so that a change to a retention class
    affects not only new data to be archived, but existing data archived with that retention
    class.<note>You must restart the nss for a change to retention class to become effective.</note>
            </li>
            <li>The Event Data Warehouse (EDW) sets the expiration timestamp in the datastore at the time of
          archive, based upon either the retention class value returned or the retention period
          specified. The EDW is unaware of any retrospective changes to the underlying Centera
          retention class. If the retention period in the original class is shortened, then the
          retire operation will still fail since ithis operation uses the expiration timestamp
          calculated at archive time. Similarly, if the retention period in the class was extended
          and the EDW attempts to delete the data from Centera, the delete operation will fail and
          the data remains in storage.</li>
            <li>The value you specify for <codeph>
                  <i>&lt;class_name&gt;</i>
               </codeph> cannot be changed. The
          Centera administrator can change the underlying retention period that the class defines.
          If you need to change the class name instead, delete and re-define the target. Use
            <codeph>deletensi</codeph> to delete the existing one and <codeph>setnsi</codeph> to
          define a new one. For more information, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-10_2_1-Defining-and-Managin_snsg.xml#topic_10_2_1"/>.</li>
            <li>When you specify data retention in a Centera NSA, enclose the entire NSA within quotation
    marks.</li>
            <li>The value you specify for a Centera NSA depends on the configuration of your system for
          failover, replication, and compliance mode, and your profile definitions. To determine how
          to specify the Centera NSA, consult the EMC Centera documentation that describes the
          parameters for the <codeph>FPPool_Open</codeph> call used by their API.</li>
            <li>If you require different retention periods for different data sources, create a separate
    NSA for each desired retention period.</li>
         </ul>
         <note type="important"> Always specify <codeph>retentionPeriod</codeph> or
          <codeph>retentionClass</codeph> on Centera. Do not specify the default. Doing so, for
        exmaple, could cause undesired retention of test data. Although certain models of Centera
        usually or always define a default retention period., if you archive data without specifying
        a retention class or period, the data may or may not already be under some form of retention
        when you archive it. Therefore, SenSage AP recommends that you <i>
               <b>always</b>
            </i> specify
        either a retention period or retention class (even if the class specifies no retention
        period).</note>
         <p>The table below illustrates the various Centera models and how they interpret retention
        classes and default retention:</p>
         <table id="table_lsf_hkq_wx">
            <tgroup cols="4">
               <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1"/>
               <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2"/>
               <colspec colnum="3" colname="col3"/>
               <colspec colnum="4" colname="col4"/>
               <thead>
                  <row>
                     <entry>Centera Package Installed</entry>
                     <entry>Default Retention Period Required?</entry>
                     <entry>Default Retention Pe- riod</entry>
                     <entry>Allowed Changes to Retention Class</entry>
                  </row>
               </thead>
               <tbody>
                  <row>
                     <entry>Basic</entry>
                     <entry/>
                     <entry/>
                     <entry>Increase or Decrease</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <entry>Governance</entry>
                     <entry/>
                     <entry/>
                     <entry>Increase or Decrease</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <entry>
                        <p>Compliance Edition  +</p>
                     </entry>
                     <entry/>
                     <entry/>
                     <entry>Only Increase</entry>
                  </row>
               </tbody>
            </tgroup>
         </table>
      </section>
   </conbody>
</concept>