<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_7_6_3">
   <title>Scheduling and the Unchanged For Attribute</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>Regardless of which element you use to set the polling frequency, you can also set how long
      source log files should remain unchanged before the retriever transfers them for processing.
      In other words, you separately specify how frequently the Collector polls for events and how
      long the Retriever keeps an event log file before it releases it for processing.</p>
      <p>To set the length of time the Retriever keeps an event log file before processing, you set
      the <codeph>&lt;UnchangedFor&gt;</codeph> attribute of the <codeph>&lt;Plugin&gt;</codeph> element. For more information about this
      element and attribute, see Plugin in “SenSage AP Collector Configuration” of the
      <cite>Collector Guide</cite>.</p>
      <p>The Collector determines when to take a file for processing based upon:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>Polling cycle<p>The frequency set either for the <codeph>&lt;Schedule&gt;</codeph> element or
          the <codeph>&lt;PollInterval&gt;</codeph> and <codeph>&lt;Period&gt;</codeph> elements</p>
        or</li>
         <li>If no values have been set for <codeph>&lt;Schedule&gt;</codeph> or
          <codeph>&lt;PollInterval&gt;</codeph> and &lt;Period&gt;, the frequency specified for
          <codeph>&lt;CycleDelay&gt;</codeph> (See CycleDelay in “SenSage AP Collector Configuration”
        of the <cite>Collector Guide</cite>)<p>and</p>
         </li>
         <li>The value specified for the <codeph>&lt;UnchangedFor&gt;</codeph> attribute of the
          <codeph>&lt;Plugin&gt;</codeph> element.<p>Each time it polls, the Collector uses the
            <codeph>&lt;UnchangedFor&gt;</codeph> setting to determine whether a file has remained
          unchanged long enough to be ready for processing.</p>
         </li>
      </ul>
      <p>Figure below illustrates how the Collector processes a file when the
        <codeph>&lt;UnchangedFor&gt;</codeph> attribute has been set to 10 minutes and the polling
      cycle has been set to 5 minutes.</p>
      <fig>
         <title>Illustrating the Relationship of Schedule Frequency &amp; UnchangedFor
       Attribute</title>
         <image href="./media/Image_204.gif" placement="break" id="image_etr_qxy_vx"/>
      </fig>
      <p>As illustrated above, a log file arrives at 1:02, which is 2 minutes after the last Collector
      poll. At 1:05 and again at 1:10, the Collector checks whether the log file has changed.
      Because the file has not changed and 10 minutes has not elapsed since the file was written,
      the Collector ignores the file at these times. However, at the 1:15 poll, because 10 minutes
      has elapsed since the file was written, the Collector takes the file for processing.</p>
      <note>The value of <codeph>&lt;CycleDelay&gt;</codeph> in <filepath>config.xml</filepath> is
      irrelevant if you set either the <codeph>&lt;Schedule&gt;</codeph> element or the
        <codeph>&lt;PollInterval&gt;</codeph> and <codeph>&lt;Period&gt;</codeph> elements.</note>
   </conbody>
</concept>