<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_4_3_6_3">
   <title>droptbl</title>
   <conbody>
      <parml>
         <plentry>
            <pt>
               <codeph>droptbl &lt;table_name&gt;</codeph>
            </pt>
            <pd>The droptbl action allows you to delete a specified table if none of its data is archived to a
          Nearline storage device. If any of its data has been archived, use the retire command to
          remove the non- archived data. Only after all of its data has been removed from the
          Nearline storage device can you drop the table. For more information, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-4_5-Retiring-Data_snsg.xml#topic_4_5"/>. <note type="important">: <ul id="ul_wcs_vyt_vx">
                     <li>Because typical EDW tables are gigantic in size, no undo is possible. Therefore,
                IgniteTech recommends that you use this action with extreme caution and that you
                back up your tables first.</li>
                     <li>When you issue <codeph>droptbl</codeph> against a table that has any data under
                retention on a Nearline storage device, the droptbl command fails. Its error message
                provides the date in the future when the Nearline storage device will retire the
                data and advises you to use retire to remove local and non-retained data.</li>
                     <li>When you issue droptbl against a table that has data archived to a Nearline
                storage device but the data is not under retention or the retention date has past,
                the droptbl command fails. Its error message informs you to use retire to remove the
                archived data before running droptbl.</li>
                  </ul>
               </note>
               <p>For more information, see <b>Installing Perl Modules</b> in “Perl
            Subroutines” in the <cite>Event Data Warehouse Guide</cite> and <xref href="c_admin_guide-4_5-Retiring-Data_snsg.xml#topic_4_5"/>.</p>
               <p>The following example deletes the table created and
            renamed in renametbl
          above:</p>
               <codeblock xml:space="preserve">atmanage slshost:8072 --namespace=external.websvcs droptbl stock_quote_log</codeblock>
            </pd>
         </plentry>
      </parml>
      <p/>
   </conbody>
</concept>