<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_9_2_1">
   <title>Consideration for Mapping User and Groups</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>his section discusses considerations for configuring AD/LDAP users and groups and how these
      objects map into a SenSage AP deployment.</p>
      <p>Before beginning Active Directory Integration for a new SenSage AP deployment, be sure to
      identify all of the users, roles, and permissions that are required. (For more information,
      see Appendix A, "SenSage AP Permission Requirements” in the <cite>SenSage AP Analyzer
        Guide</cite>.</p>
      <p>If you are integrating an existing deployment, note all of the roles and users prior to
      beginning the integration. When each SenSage AP user is defined, roles and groups are
      associated with each user. A user’s role are the union of all their direct roles.</p>
      <p>Consider the following when mapping users and roles:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>Roles are local to Analyzer only and are not mapped in AD/LDAP. You configure SenSage AP
       authorization in the Role tab of SenSage AP Analyzer by granting permissions to roles. These
       permissions authorize SenSage AP users to access specific features and data in Analyzer.</li>
         <li>.When you configure AD/LDAP integration, AD groups and users that are members of the
        specified AD domain are automatically mapped to SenSage AP when users and groups are
        synchronized in Analyzer.<note>Users are synchronized from configured AD servers to SenSage
          AP on demand (for a single-server only) or on schedule (all AD-servers). A LDAP scheduling
          screen is provided in Analyzer to set up a schedule and a button is provided to update
          users from LDAP on demand. For details on using this feature, see the <cite>SenSage AP
            Analyzer Guide.</cite>
            </note>
         </li>
         <li>It is possible that users from multiple domains have the same "SAM Account Name". In this
        case, you should map all of the Active Directory users to different Analyzer users. For
        example, if there were two users with SAM Account Names of <b>Bob</b> in <b>domain1</b> and
          <b>Bob</b> in <b>domain2</b>, the duplicate user is skipped. <p>Since a user already gets
          created with the username <b>bob</b> after synchronization, for the second user, you need
          to create a user account with the username as <b>Bob1</b> in Analyzer (as shown below) and
          map the user to the appropriate AD. Users will then be able to log into Analyzer with
          unique names. Analyzer will map these unique names to the proper user account that is
          identified with the account’s DN in the specific AD server where that account is defined.
          The user is then authenticated by the AD server according to the DN selected. </p>
         </li>
      </ul>
      <fig>
         <title> Mapping SAM Account Names</title>
         <image href="./media/Image_253.jpg" placement="break"/>
      </fig>
   </conbody>
</concept>