<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_4_3_6_7">
   <title>compacttbl</title>
   <conbody>
      <parml>
         <plentry>
            <pt>
               <codeph>compacttbl &lt;table_name&gt; [&lt;num_seconds&gt;] [&lt;enable_compact_archived_data&gt;][&lt;number&gt;d/m/h]</codeph>
            </pt>
            <pd>By default, the EDW loads new data into separately indexed fragments to avoid the
          overhead associated with combining data into more efficient files for long-term archival.
          If you have many loads in the same time range (especially small loads under 10,000
          records), query performance and/or compression can suffer. <p>Optionally you can use this
            utility to compact archived data as well as local data. To do so, set <codeph>
                     <i>&lt;enable_compact_archived_data&gt;</i>
                  </codeph> to <codeph>1</codeph>. You can also
            set the number of seconds compacting occurs before it stops. The following example
            compacts local and archived data for <b>myTable</b>; compacting stops after 10 minutes
            (600 seconds).</p>
               <p>
                  <codeph>compacttbl myTable 600 1</codeph>
               </p>
               <p>Set the duration to
            run compact on recent data by providing the last days, minutes, and hours. Specify the
            duration using the following syntax:</p>
               <p>
                  <codeph>[&lt;number&gt;d/m/h]</codeph>
               </p>
               <p>The
            following example compacts local and archived data for myTable for the last 2 days;
            compacting stops after 10 minutes (600 seconds).</p>
               <p>
                  <codeph>compacttbl myTable 600 1
              2d</codeph>
               </p>
               <p>Assuming that the current date and time is April 25th, 2016
            11:40:00, in this example, the manual compact tool will compact leaves with timestamp
            from April 23rd, 2016 00:00:00 till the current timestamp the case of days, a day is
            always calculated from the start of the specified day (00:00 hours) till the current
            date and is not calculated based on current hours and minutes.</p>
               <p>Similarly, the
            following example compacts local and archived data for the last 30 minutes; compacting
            stops after 10 minutes (600 seconds).</p>
               <p>
                  <codeph>compacttbl myTable 600 1
              30m</codeph>
               </p>
               <p>Assuming that the current date and time is April 25th, 2016
            11:40:00, in this example, the manual compact tool will compact leaves with timestamp
            from April 25th, 2016 11:10:00 till the current timestamp.</p>
               <p>The following example
            compacts local and archived data for the last 4 hours.</p>
               <p>
                  <codeph>compacttbl myTable
              600 1 4h</codeph>
               </p>
               <p>Assuming that the current date and time is April 25th, 2016
            11:40:00, in this example, the manual compact tool will compact leaves from April 25th,
            2016 7:40:00 till the current timestamp.</p>
               <p>
                  <note>One day is not calculated as 24 hours, make sure that you set the compact duration
              appropriately.</note>
               </p>
               <note type="important">This command cannot compact any node that stores data archived
            to a Nearline storage device. Only after the retention period has ended can the Nearline
            storage data be compacted. For more information, see: <ul id="ul_ghr_gd5_vx">
                     <li>Installing Perl Modules in Chapter 8, “Perl Subroutines” in the Event Data
                Warehouse Guide</li>
                     <li>Compact in Chapter 2, “SenSage AP Collector Configuration” in the Collector
                Guide</li>
                  </ul>
               </note>
               <note type="important">: Consult IgniteTech Support before using this
            command, because it can be very slow and often yields little improvement.</note>
            </pd>
         </plentry>
      </parml>
   </conbody>
</concept>