<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_3_2">
   <title>Monitoring SenSage AP</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>To the left of the dashboard is a summary of the nodes and the components that make up your
      deployment. You can start and stop any of the components from the dashboard. You can browse
      quickly through the display of icons beside each component. If a "Start" icon is displayed
      beside a component, this can alert you that the component is not in operation.</p>
      <p>From this dashboard, you monitor your cluster by viewing the Cluster Metrics graphs displayed
      to the right, which show the current usage for the network, cluster load, memory and CPU. Note
      that clicking on the icon in the corner of the Cluster Metrics area pulls up different graph
      timetables for your selection.</p>
      <fig id="fid_g_2_1">
         <title>Deployment Manager Dashboard</title>
         <image href="./media/Image_021.jpg" id="image_ly2_ndh_vx" placement="break"/>
      </fig>
      <p>For details on Cluster Metrics graphs, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-3_3_3-Metrics_snsg.xml#topic_3_3_3"/>. </p>
      <p>Two tabs that allow you to monitor specific parts of your deployment:</p>
      <ul id="ul_tzr_qdh_vx">
         <li>
            <b>Service tab</b> - Shows the status of the services in your SenSage AP
          deployment.<note>In addition, this tab also contains a configuration link lets you change
          the configuration settings from the initial installation. For details, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-3_5-Modifying-Installati_snsg.xml#topic_3_5"/>.</note>
         </li>
         <li>
            <b>Host tab</b> - Shows the status of components in your SenSage AP deployment on a
        host-by-host basis.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Each of these tabs and their options are described in the following sections.</p>
   </conbody>
</concept>