<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_9_6">
   <title>FAQs</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>
         <b>What if I want to use the AD Administrator account to log in to AP Analyzer? Do I need to
        have the AD Administrator added to the Hexis OU?</b>
      </p>
      <p>No, any user is supported on any Domains and OUs and is not required to be part of the same
      pattern. However, if the account is not part of the pattern it will not be synchronized
      whenever the synchronization process is run; if it is part of the pattern, it will be
      synchronized. To use the AD</p>
      <p>Administrator account to log into AP Analyzer, if the SAM account name of the AD
      Administrator matches with the default SAM account of Analyzer Admin, upon sync, the account
      is updated and you can log in using the AD Administrator account. In case of a different SAM
      account (other than Admin), you need to only assign admin roles to this account (using Edit
      User screen).</p>
      <p>
         <b>Can I selectively change the settings of a user from the Analyzer GUI?</b>
      </p>
      <p>Yes, you can, but these changes will be over-written with settings from AD whenever the user
      database is synchronized with AD. The AD synchronization updates all fields of all users,
      whose name matches the SAM account field in AD, and if the account was originally created from
      synchronizing with the same AD. An Analyzer user account that has no corresponding SAM account
      in the AD is not updated. An Analyzer user account that is synchronized with one AD server
      already will not be updated by synchronizing any other AD servers.</p>
      <p>
         <b>How do I delete a user?</b>
      </p>
      <p>To delete a user, you must first remove the user account in AD. Then, remove the user account
      in Analyzer. This is because the AD synchronization will not cause any user to be deleted in
      the Analyzer.</p>
      <p>
         <b>If I delete a user in the Analyzer, will the user re-appear whenever AD synchronization
        happens next?</b>
      </p>
      <p>Yes, it will appear as long as the user is not deleted from AD. </p>
      <p>
         <b>How does AD synchronization work in a multi-realm environment?</b>
      </p>
      <p>If there are multiple accounts with the same SAM account field, then all of them except for
      the first one should be given a unique name in the Analyzer and separately synced to the
      respective AD servers. For example, if there are two accounts with <b>Bob</b> in the SAM
      account field in two different AD servers, then the first one is synced and an Analyzer
      account named <b>Bob</b> will be mapped to it. None of the other accounts with the SAM name
        <b>Bob</b> will be mapped to the Analyzer when it is synchronized with them. The Analyzer
      administrator must create <b>Bob2</b> in the Analyzer and manually map that user to the second
      AD server.</p>
   </conbody>
</concept>