<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_4_5_2">
   <title>Description</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>The retire command is a SenSage AP SQL extension rather than a command-line tool and,
      therefore, is unlike the utilities documented in this chapter. You do not run retire from the
      command line as you do the utilities. Instead, you use the <codeph>atquery</codeph> utility to
      run it.</p>
      <p>The retire command replaces the deprecated <codeph>atretire</codeph> utility as the tool for
      retiring data from an EDW</p>
      <p>instance. The retire command provides significantly enhanced performance over
        <codeph>atretire</codeph>.</p>
      <p>Moreover, the syntax of the <codeph>retire</codeph> command is easier and more comprehensive
      than that of the <codeph>atretire</codeph> command. While the <codeph>atretire</codeph>
      command required you to specify the cutoff time in the predefined syntax of a timestamp, the
      retire command allows you to specify the cutoff time as any SenSage AP SQL expression that
      evaluates to a timestamp data type.</p>
      <p>The retire command permanently deletes data from the specified table in the EDW instance. Use
      this command to:</p>
      <ul id="ul_wfp_pl5_vx">
         <li>Reclaim Space<p>Although the combination of EDW compression and ever-increasing disk
          capacity has reduced the urgency of deleting older data, there are still applications that
          require this regular maintenance. You can use <codeph>retire</codeph> to delete old data,
          retiring on a range of upload IDs or timestamps.</p>
            <note type="important"> Retiring data from an
          EDW table removes only data that is not stored under retention on a Nearline storage
          device. The command skips archived data that is under retention and returns a message that
          provides the date in the future when the Nearline storage device will retire the data.
          That date is the earliest you can retire the data. The command does remove archived data
          that is not under retention or its retention period has passed. On some Nearline storage
          devices, however, in order to ensure retire time specifications are enforced, the command
          may be required to restore some data not under retention and let it remain online even
          though it falls outside the retire date. For more information on Nearline storage, see
            <xref href="c_admin_guide-10-ARCHIVING-TONEARLIN_snsg.xml#topic_10"/>.</note>
         </li>
         <li>Undo Duplicate Loads<p>Occasionally, the same log file is accidentally loaded twice. You
          can use retire to remove one of the copies. You delete based on upload ID.</p>
         </li>
         <li>Undo Loads Containing Bad Data <p>Occasionally, the source data itself is incorrect, and
          you want to fix the data in the long-term archives. If the problem is limited to one log
          file, IgniteTech recommends backing out this one file, fixing the source data, then
          reloading. However, if the corruption occurred over the course of weeks, it may be
          preferable to use retire to delete selected records.</p>
         </li>
      </ul>
   </conbody>
</concept>