<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_4_1_10">
   <title>Tracking Uploads in the EDW</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>In addition to loading the log data into the specified table(s), atload saves information in
      the EDW about the load. You can view this information by querying against two system
      tables:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>
            <codeph>system.upload_info</codeph>
            <p>This table enables administrators to check on upload
          status in the system. When the system is healthy, this table returns one row for each
          upload. When the upload data is not consistent across all the hosts in the instance, this
          table returns a value of <codeph>false</codeph> in the CONSISTENT column for this case,
          the table may return multiple rows with the same value in the <codeph>_uploadid</codeph>
          column; all of these rows are marked as inconsistent.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <codeph>system.raw_upload_info</codeph>
            <p>This table enables a support person to troubleshoot an inconsistency problem by seeing the
       raw data distributed across the system</p>
         </li>
      </ul>
      <p>Both of these tables contain a unique identifier for the upload: the value of the _uploadid
      column. For more information about the _uploadid column, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-4_5_7_1-Using-the-UPLOADS-Co_snsg.xml#topic_4_5_7_1"/>
      and <xref href="c_admin_guide-4_3_6-Table-Management_snsg.xml#topic_4_3_6"/>.</p>
      <p>These tables store additional information that includes: the minimum and maximum timestamps,
      the number of lines in the source log data, the number of lines successfully parsed by the
      PTL, the number of rows loaded into the specified EDW table(s), the PTL and client signatures,
      and whether the load was successful.</p>
      <p>Additionally, the <codeph>system.upload_info</codeph> table returns the consistency data and
      the</p>
      <p>
         <codeph>system.raw_upload_info</codeph> returns the logical name of the data's source
      host.</p>
      <p>As it begins loading data into the log tables, the EDW inserts a new row in these system
      tables to track the uploaditially, the value of the SUCCESSFUL column defaults to false.
      When the load completes successfully, this column's value changes to true. By default, when
      you query the data in the log table(s), the EDW returns data only for loads that completed
      successfully. If you query a log table while it is still receiving data, none of the new data
      is returned.</p>
      <note>To view data from a failed load or from an in-progress load, specify the
        <codeph>{INCLUDE_BAD_UPLOADS}</codeph> modifier (enclosed within curly braces) in the
        <codeph>FROM</codeph> clause of your query. If a query and a load occur simultaneously and
      the query continues after the load completes, you may see all, none, or part of the data from
      the new load.</note>
      <p>For more information, see:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>"system.upload_info” and “system.raw_upload_info” in the <cite>Event Data Warehouse
          Guide</cite>.</li>
         <li>"Including Rows from Bad Loads" in “SenSage AP SQL” of the <cite>Event Data Warehouse
          Guide</cite>.</li>
         <li>
            <xref href="c_admin_guide-11_2-Checking-Locking-Sta_snsg.xml#topic_11_2"/>
         </li>
      </ul>
   </conbody>
</concept>