<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_2_1_1">
   <title>Overview of SenSage AP Components and Processing</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>The SenSage AP system supports the industry's most comprehensive event management
      capabilities. Its patented data model and compression technology facilitate online storage of
      massive volumes of data across an entire network. The SenSage AP architecture enables rapid
      querying of and visibility into security threats.</p>
      <p>Linear scalability through clustering provides the flexibility needed to support new
      applications and devices as requirements growtegration capabilities allow SenSage AP to
      use external enterprise authentication authorities to validate and manage SenSage AP users and
      external Nearline storage devices to archive SenSage AP data addition, you can forward
      alerts to enterprise security management products, pagers, phones, and portals.</p>
      <p>A SenSage AP system comprises the following core components:</p>
      <ul id="ul_oxy_xxg_vx">
         <li>
            <b>Event Data Warehouse (EDW)</b>—stores event data from multiple sources in a scalable and
        highly compressed format. Parallel processing enables clustered servers to execute as a
        single instance, allowing high-speed loading and querying on terabytes of data.<ul>
               <li>
                  <b> Analyzer</b>—Command-line utilities communicate with the Analyzer to access stored
            data and configuration information. The Analyzer lets authorized users view reports,
            alerts, and dashboards, manage assets, enable and disable Parser rules, run reports,
            schedule jobs, and manage users and roles. The Application Manager is implemented as a
            set of services that run within a Tomcat Application Server, which is installed and
            configured transparently during installation of SenSage AP software.</li>
               <li>
                  <b>Open Access Extension (OAE)</b>—provides access to data stored in the EDW via
            standard database connectivity tools such as ODBC and JDBC.</li>
               <li>
                  <b>LDAP</b>—provides authentication services for a SenSage AP deployment.</li>
            </ul>
         </li>
         <li>
            <b>Collector</b>—pulls event data from disparate sources. It uses retrievers that define how
        the Collector obtains batched event data from event sources and log adapters that define how
        incoming batched data is parsed and stored in the EDW. The Collector uses a file system
        retriever to pull data that is stored in syslog-ng, the industry standard in receiving event
        data from internal and external sources.</li>
         <li>
            <b>Syslog-ng</b>—The industry standard in bifurcating data into the batch modes.</li>
      </ul>
      <fig>
         <title>SenSage AP Architecture and Data</title>
         <image href="./media/Image_015.jpg" placement="break"/>
      </fig>
      <p>The above figure illustrates the complete SenSage AP architecture. As illustrated, events
      enter the SenSage AP system from any of many external systems, such as network devices and
      software applications. Events enter in the following way:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>Batched—Events are collected from log files and other event repositories maintained by
      network devices, operating systems, and software applications.</li>
         <li>The Collector polls a data source or repository to retrieve event data, which it loads into
      the EDW. The EDW makes the event data available to the Analyzer for reporting. Administration
      users can access EDW data using the Deployment Manager.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>For more information:</p>
      <ul>
         <li> To learn more about configuring retrievers and the Collector, see the chapter <b>SenSage AP
          Collector Configuration</b> in the<cite> Collector Guide</cite>.</li>
         <li> To learn more about administering the Collector, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-7-Administering-the-Co_snsg.xml#topic_7"/>.</li>
         <li> For more information about the EDW and SenSage AP SQL: <ul id="ul_pml_kzg_vx">
               <li>see, chapters <xref href="c_admin_guide-3-ManagingSensageAP_snsg.xml#topic_3"/> and <xref href="c_admin_guide-4-Sensage-Loading-Que_snsg.xml#topic_4"/> of this
            guide.</li>
               <li>see, chapters <b>SenSage AP SQL</b> and <b>SenSage AP ConsoleSenSage AP SQL
              Functions</b> of the <cite>Event Data Warehouse Guide</cite>.</li>
            </ul>
         </li>
      </ul>
   </conbody>
</concept>