<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_2_1">
   <title id="title_a3">Overview of SenSage AP System Administration</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>SenSage AP system administrators work mostly in a Linux environment and should be comfortable
      using Linux in command-line mode. Administrators should also be familiar with SSH, managing
      users and groups, file system permissions and management, network configuration, logging, and
      using such text editors as VI or emacs.</p>
      <p>If your SenSage AP deployment collects log data from Windows machines, firewalls, routers, or
      applications, familiarity with those systems is also required.</p>
      <p>SenSage AP system administrators perform the following tasks:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>
            <b>Installation and configuration</b>—Installation and initial configuration of your
        SenSage AP software is discussed in the <cite>Installation, Configuration, and Upgrade
          Guide</cite>.</li>
         <li>
            <b>Upgrading</b>—Upgrading your SenSage AP deployment to a newer version is discussed in
          <i>Example Upgrade Path</i> in Chapter 4 of the <cite>Installation, Configuration, and
          Upgrade Guide</cite>.</li>
         <li>
            <b>Administration</b>—Administration tasks discussed in this manual include: <ul>
               <li> Configuring batch collection of event data—After basic installation, you configure
            SenSage AP to collect batched event data by installing log adapters and configuring the
            Collector, Retrievers, and Loaders.</li>
               <li> Managing the EDW data store—As you configure SenSage AP, you load test data and run
            test queries against that data. You can also create tables, views, and column filters,
            manage users and permissions for data access, monitor performance, and archive or retire
            data.</li>
               <li> Managing the EDW instance—You configure and manage clustered nodes in an EDW instance
            and configure Nearline storage devices.</li>
               <li> Manage Near-line storage—you can archive event data stored in the EDW to a variety of
            Nearline storage devices such as EMC Centera, and Remote NFS (Network) or CIFS (Common
            Internet) File System.</li>
               <li> Backing up and restoring event data and raw log files.</li>
               <li> Managing users, permissions and authentication—Permissions for your SenSage AP
            deployment and its users must be managed carefully to limit access to information and
            ensure a secure environment.</li>
               <li> Managing the report cache—You manage the retention of cached report data.</li>
               <li> Network configuration—You configure network connections between SenSage AP components
            and the machines or devices from which you are collecting event data.</li>
               <li> Monitoring system performance and source health—Your SenSage AP software provides
            tools to monitor the performance of the SenSage AP deployment. You configure these
            components to issue alerts when performance is diminished or event data collection is
            interrupted.</li>
            </ul>
         </li>
      </ul>
   </conbody>
</concept>