<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_3_5">
   <title id="title_a7">Modifying Installation Configuration Settings</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>The Config tab on the Services page allows you view existing parameter settings and change
      those affected by any updates you have made to your deployment. Click the
        <uicontrol>Configs</uicontrol> link shown below to bring up the Configuration page (Figure
      2-27)</p>
      <fig>
         <title> Configuration Link (NEW SCREENSHOT)</title>
         <image href="./media/Image_057.jpg" placement="break"/>
      </fig>
      <p>Scroll through the Configuration page to find the parameter settings that you need to change.
      Description for the parameters are available when you hover your mouse over each of the
      parameter fields. Those parameters that you cannot change are grayed out or left blank.</p>
      <draft-comment author="Hemraj" translate="no">NEED NEW
        SCREENSHOT</draft-comment>
      <fig>
         <title> First Section of Configuration Page</title>
         <image href="./media/Image_058.jpg" placement="break"/>
      </fig>
      <p>The following table describes the Analyzer configuration parameters on the configuration
      page. These parameters</p>
      <table id="table_ixt_3lh_vx">
         <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1"/>
            <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2"/>
            <thead>
               <row>
                  <entry>Configuration Parameter</entry>
                  <entry>Description</entry>
               </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
               <row>
                  <entry>LDAP/AD Base URL</entry>
                  <entry>This is the LDAP/AD Base URL for the Active Directory Server in a single-server
              environment or the base URL for the first server defined in a multi-server environment
              (in which the remaining servers are defined directly in the properties file.</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>LDAP/AD Server URL</entry>
                  <entry>This is the LDAP/AD Server UURL for the Active Directory Server in a
              single-server environment or the base URL for the first server defined in a
              multi-server environment (in which the remaining servers are defined directly in the
              properties file.</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>LDAP/AD Manager DN</entry>
                  <entry>This is the distinguished name that uniquely identifes an entry in the LDAP
              Directory Information Tree and in this case represents the Common Name (CN),
              Organizational Unit (OU), and Domain Component (DC). This entry cannot be changed.
                <draft-comment author="Hemraj" translate="no">Is this correct or not changed the first
                time?</draft-comment>For example:
              <codeblock xml:space="preserve">CN=analyzeradmin,OU=hexis,DC=customer,DC=com
CN=analyzeradmin</codeblock>
                  </entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>LDAP/AD Username</entry>
                  <entry>The user name of the Analyzer Administrator.</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>LDAP/AD Password</entry>
                  <entry>The password of the Analyzer Administrator.</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>LDAP/AD Password to authenticate</entry>
                  <entry>The LDAP password to authenticate with LDAP/AD- NEED MORE DETAIL</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>LDAP/AD User pattern</entry>
                  <entry>The required user pattern in the following format:
              CN=users,DC=dev-ap,DC=local</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>Test Connection</entry>
                  <entry>Used to check whether the credentials (defined above) are accurately
              configured.</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>SMTP Port</entry>
                  <entry>Port on which the SMTP server listens and is used for emails. <draft-comment author="Hemraj" translate="no">IS THERE A COMMON PORT NUMBER FOR THIS?</draft-comment>
                  </entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>SMTP Authenticate Users</entry>
                  <entry>The SMTP login user that is used to send emails.</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>SMTP Password</entry>
                  <entry>The password for the SMTP user.</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>SMTP From</entry>
                  <entry>The originating user<draft-comment author="Hemraj" translate="no">???</draft-comment> for
              SMTP</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>SMTP From Email Address</entry>
                  <entry>The originating email address for SMTP</entry>
               </row>
               <row>
                  <entry>SMTP Start TLS Enables</entry>
                  <entry>Used to enable secure connections to send emails.</entry>
               </row>
            </tbody>
         </tgroup>
      </table>
      <p>
         <draft-comment author="Hemraj" translate="no">ALL OF THESE PARMETERS NEED MORE DETAIL (SEE FIRST
        ONE)</draft-comment>
      </p>
      <section>
         <title>Configuring SSL for the Deployment Manager</title>
         <p>Connections to the Deployment Manager are protected by SSL, using a self-signed SSL
        certificate that is generated automatically during the installation or upgrade process. You
        can replace the automatically generated self-signed SSL certificate with your own
        certificate. For more information, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-3_5_1-Using-a-Custom-SSL-C_snsg.xml#topic_3_5_1"/>. The self- signed SSL
        certificate is valid for one year. You can replace an expired certificate for the Deployment
        Manager (see <xref href="c_admin_guide-3_5_2-Replacing-an-Expired_snsg.xml#topic_3_5_2"/>) and the Analyzer (see <xref href="c_admin_guide-3_5_3-Using-a-Custom-Certi_snsg.xml#topic_3_5_3"/>).</p>
         <p>Additionally, the Deployment Manager manages AP components on each host of the AP
            cluster via SSL connections, using SSL certificates that were generated during
            installation on each AP host in the cluster. These certificates are set to expire in 3
            years. When the certificates expire, the Deployment Manager will be unable to manage the
            hosts in the AP cluster, although the AP functions will continue to work. To re-enable
            the Deployment Manager's capability to manage the AP cluster after the SSL certificate
            expires, follow the procedure described in <xref
               href="c_admin_guide-3_5_4-Replacing-Expired-SS_snsg.xml#topic_3_5_4"/>.</p>
      </section>
   </conbody>
</concept>