<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_9_2">
   <title id="title_a38">What you Need to Know before Integrating Active Directory/LDAP</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>You can configure AD/LDAP integration on a new SenSage AP deployment or migrate an existing
      SenSage AP deployment to use AD integration. Whether you are using a new deployment or
      migrating to an existing one, the process is the same.</p>
      <p>Following is a brief overview of the AD/LDAP preparation, configuration, and integration
      process. The actual configuration and integration steps are described in detail in Setting Up
      Active Directory.</p>
      <ol>
         <li>To prepare for AD/LDAP integration:<ol>
               <li>The AD Administrator creates a AD/LDAP Enumerator user account; a default Analyzer
            "Admin" that is already in the Analyzer system will be mapped to the AD (enumerator)
                user.<note type="important">: User names are case sensitive in SenSage AP and Active
              Directory will preserve the case of the name as entered by the AD Administrator into
              the SAM field, from which AP user names are derived.</note>
               </li>
               <li>For a new SenSage AP deployment, an administrator is required to identify all users,
            roles and permissions in the organization. For an existing deployment, an administrator
            is required to identify all existing roles and users prior to beginning the integration.
            For details, see the following section, <i>Mapping Users and Groups</i>.</li>
               <li>In the Active Directory Console, the AD Administrator adds a <b>hexis</b> OU and adds
            any desired users and groups to the OU (directory or via OU Association).</li>
            </ol>
         </li>
         <li>To perform set up tasks such as user sync or group sync, the Analyzer "Admin" is required
        to log into the Analyzer for the first time with the AD Enumerator DN password.</li>
         <li>In Deployment Manager, the SenSage AP Service Configuration screen is used to configure a
        single AD server as noted in <xref href="c_admin_guide-9_3_3-Configuring-Single-A_snsg.xml#topic_9_3_3"/>. Additional servers must be
        configured in the Analyzer Host as noted in <xref href="c_admin_guide-9_3_4-Configuring-Multiple_snsg.xml#topic_9_3_4"/>.</li>
         <li>In AP Analyzer, the Analyzer "Admin" can populate users by synchronizing with AD
        immediately, or by creating a schedule to synchronize periodically. The Analyzer "Admin" can
        also edit the populated user accounts and add additional accounts manually through mapping
        AD server mapping details to each user account.</li>
         <li>In AP Analyzer, the Analyzer "Admin" can create a group and synchronize the group with
        the selected AD/LDAP server mapping details.</li>
      </ol>
      <p>
         <note>When groups are synchronized from Analyzer, all <i>existing</i> users (if migrating to
        AD/LDAP from an existing SenSage AP deployment) under the specified DN pattern will be
        updated in Analyzer. This means that the membership group in Analyzer will match the
        membership of the group in AD.</note>
      </p>
   </conbody>
</concept>