<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_10_1_2">
   <title>Types of Nearline Storage Space</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>You can use the SenSage AP Nearline Storage Server (NSS) to archive data to the following
      Nearline storage devices:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>
            <b>EMC® Centera™ Nearline Storage Driver</b>
            <p>This module allows your organization to take advantage of the unique compliance features that
       Centera provides. The EDW uses the proprietary Centera API to move data to and from the
       Centera device.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <b>Remote NFS (Network) or CIFS (Common Internet) File System</b>
            <p>Remote file systems allow your organization to archive historical data to regular storage
       devices on remote hosts. The remote file systems are mounted locally on the hosts where the
       EDW instance runs. The local mount points on all EDW hosts must be the same, but each mount
       point can reference a different remote file system.</p>
         </li>
      </ul>
      <p>In summary, Nearline storage provides:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>Easier management of storage space. Scheduling the archiving of data to Nearline storage
         helps you maintain sufficient local storage space for EDW instances.</li>
         <li>Easier expansion of storage space. If you require more space, add more storage to your
         SenSage AP-supported Nearline storage device.</li>
         <li>More evenly balanced data loads on EDW hosts. When you add hosts to an EDW instance, the
         newer hosts initially have less data on them than the older, existing hosts. Because older
         data is archived before newer data, older hosts in the EDW instance are generally the first to
         reclaim local storage space.</li>
         <li>Automatic retrieval of archived data. When people run queries, they do not need to know
         whether the are retrieved from local or Nearline storage.</li>
      </ul>
   </conbody>
</concept>