<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_1_4">
   <title id="title_a2">How to Obtain the SenSage AP License</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>Beginning with SenSage AP 5.0.0, you are required to have a license key to run your cluster.
      Each EDW cluster will require its own, valid license key. Trying to upgrade to 6.1.1 without a
      valid license will cause the upgrade to fail.</p>
      <p>Your license is contained in a license key file that you must copy to each EDW node in your
      cluster. A successful query against your EDW cluster confirms that you have correctly
      installed a valid license key for your cluster.</p>
      <p>If you haven’t received your license key, contact your IgniteTech representative. When you
      receive the key, you need to copy it over to the following placeholder files on each EDW node
      in your cluster.</p>
      <p>
         <filepath>&lt;install-root&gt;/etc/sls/instance/&lt;cluster-name&gt;/LICENSE</filepath>
      </p>
      <p>When the new license key, LICENSE, is copied to all EDW nodes, you can restart each EDW
      normally.</p>
      <p>Do not alter the license key file in any way. Even a whitespace change will render the file
      invalid as the embedded digital signature is computed against the exact sequence of bytes in
      the original license key file.</p>
      <p>If there is an issue with the LICENSE file, you will see one of the following errors when
      submitting queries to the EDW cluster:</p>
      <p>Trial License has expired - The license was tied to a trial period, which has expired.</p>
      <p>Missing or Invalid License -The LICENSE file specified in the athttpd.conf file on some node
      is not valid or is missing.</p>
      <p>EDW configured for more cores then the license allows - The number of physical cores that the
      cluster is configured to use is larger than the licensed limit.</p>
      <p>Product is operating under a Trial License and evidence of clock tampering has been noted -
      the system is running under a trial license and there is evidence that the system clock has
      been pushed back.</p>
      <p>
         <note>"Cluster size" is defined in terms of physical cores. Many Intel CPUs support
        hyperthreading in which a single physical core appears to the Linux kernel as two logical
        cores. The <filepath>cluster.xml</filepath> file defines how many logical cores each EDW node will use. The EDW
        licensing logic looks at the <filepath>cluster.xml</filepath> file and the hardware that the EDW is running on to
        determine the total number of physical cores that the cluster has been configured to use. If the <filepath>cluster.xml</filepath> file does not specify a number of cores for an EDW node, it is
        assumed that it will use all cores on that server.</note>
      </p>
      <p>If you need to resolve a licensing issue, contact IgniteTech Support.</p>
   </conbody>
</concept>