<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_5_1_1">
   <title>How the Event Data Warehouse (EDW) Queues Tasks</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>The EDW has three queues: one for Normal Priority processes, one for Critical Priority
      processes, and one for Urgent Priority processes. The first two of these queues are defined
      in:</p>
      <p>
         <filepath>/opt/hexis/hawkeye-ap/etc/sls/instance/&lt;instance_name&gt;/athttpd.conf</filepath>
      </p>
      <p>as:</p>
      <ul id="ul_uwx_ds5_vx">
         <li>
            <codeph>normalrunqueuequota</codeph> (default <codeph>3</codeph>)</li>
         <li>
            <codeph>criticalrunqueuequota</codeph> (default <codeph>10</codeph>)</li>
      </ul>
      <note>These queues are set in the Deployment Manager’s Advanced EDW section (under the HawEye
      AP service Configs tab) in the fields "EDW normal run queue quota" and "EDW critical run queue
      quota".</note>
      <p>The third process, <codeph>UrgentRunQueueQuota</codeph>, cannot be configured. This process
      has an infinite depth, which means it can run an infinite number of jobs. The EDW immediately
      runs everything on this queue)</p>
      <p>The command "<codeph>atmanage canceltask</codeph>" has urgent priority by default, all other
      tasks have normal priority. Therefore the <codeph>--skip-queues</codeph> option is not
      necessary for cancels to work on a loaded system.</p>
      <p>The Normal and Critical queues independently allow a set number of requests to run
      simultaneously. (This number can be changed for these queues, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-5_2-Backup-and-Restore_snsg.xml#topic_5_2"/>).</p>
      <p>If there are more requests of a given priority than can be run simultaneously, the later
      requests will be blocked until an earlier request completes. Blocked tasks are marked as
        <codeph>EVENT_WAIT</codeph> in the state column of the <codeph>system.task_list</codeph>
      table.</p>
   </conbody>
</concept>