<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_9_3_3">
   <title>Configuring Single-AD Integration</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>Follow these steps if you have a single-AD server environment. Otherwise, go to the next
      section to configure a multi-AD server environment.</p>
      <ol>
         <li>From the Deployment Manager console, go to the Services tab and select the SenSage AP
        cluster link.</li>
         <li>Stop the SenSage AP cluster.</li>
         <li>Under the Analyzer Server section of the Configs tab, select the “ad” option and provide
        the following settings as shown in see Figure 8-3.<draft-comment translate="no">SCREENSHOT NEEDED WITHOUT
          RED BOX - PLEASE PROVIDE FULL AMBARI SCREENSHOT <u>WHICH IS NEEDED FOR INSTALLATION GUIDE
            AND OTHER SECTION OF ADMIN GUIDE</u>
            </draft-comment>
            <fig>
               <title> Configuring a Single-AD Server</title>
               <image href="./media/Image_265.jpg" placement="break" id="image_esd_gb4_wx"/>
            </fig>
         </li>
         <li>In the LDAP/AD Base URL field, provide the URL connection string for your first or only
        AD. For example:<codeblock xml:space="preserve">ldap://ad_host.customer.com:389</codeblock>
         </li>
         <li>In the LDAP/AD Enumerator DN field, provide the enumerator account details. For
        example:<codeblock xml:space="preserve">CN=analyzeradmin,OU=org,DC=customer,DC=com</codeblock>
         </li>
         <li>In the LDAP/AD Password field, provide the password for the AD enumerator (Enumerator
          DN).<draft-comment translate="no">IN STEP 7, THE EXAMPLE PROVIDED IS THE ANALYZER ADMIN. WHY DO YOU SAY
          THAT THE USER MUST ENTER THE FULL DISTINGUISHED NAME OF THE "SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR? "ARE
          YOU REALLY IMPLYING THE USER CAN BE WHATEVER AD USER IS SET AS LONG AS IT IS A VALID SAM
          ACCOUNT? SEE WHERE I GOT THE TERM "SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR" BELOW STEP 7 <u>FROM YOUR
            DESCRIPTION.</u>
            </draft-comment>
         </li>
         <li>In the LDAP/AD Admin DN field, provide the fully-distinguished name of the System
        Administrator in AD. For example:
          <codeblock xml:space="preserve">CN=analyzer admin,OU=org,DC=customer,DC=com</codeblock>
            <draft-comment translate="no">The value
          that the user enters into the "LDAP/AD Admin DN" field will be the full distinguished name
          of the system administrator in LDAP or AD. The system will lookup this user in the first
          server as configured on the same screen. It will find the Sam Account name of the user. It
          will than make the necessary changes to the Analyzer administrative account (which by
          default is "admin") so that the Username of the administrative user becomes the Sam
          Account name of <u>the entered DN.</u>
            </draft-comment>
            <note>All LDAP elements (like CN and
          OU) must be in uppercase.</note>
         </li>
         <li>In the LDAP/AD User Pattern, enter the required AD user pattern. For
        example:<codeblock xml:space="preserve">CN=Users,DC=dev-ap,DC=local</codeblock>
         </li>
         <li>Save the changes and start the SenSage AP cluster.</li>
         <li>Go to <xref href="c_admin_guide-9_3_5-UpdatingScheduling-_snsg.xml#topic_9_3_5"/> to synchronize users to the AD server.</li>
      </ol>
   </conbody>
</concept>