<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_5_8">
   <title id="title_a24">System Tables</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>You can query the EDW to get information about your SenSage AP system such as the state of an
      EDW instance or all defined roles and which users have been assigned to them. When you query
      for this information, the EDW dynamically formats the result data as a standard table.</p>
      <p>These tables return system information and are known as <i>system tables</i>. Because the
      data returned is not saved on disk but is dynamically retrieved and formatted as a standard
      table, they are also referred to as <i>virtual tables</i>. For a detailed description of each
      system table, refer to <i>Appendix D: SenSage APSystem Tables</i> of the <cite>Event Data
        Warehouse Guide</cite>.</p>
      <p>The virtual nature of these tables is apparent when you query the EDW for all tables in your
      instance by running the atview command; for example:</p>
      <codeblock xml:space="preserve">atview --user=administrator --pass=&lt;<i>passwd</i>&gt; --namespace='' &lt;<i>cluster_list</i>&gt; tables</codeblock>
      <p>The above command does not return any system tables.</p>
      <p>Because the system tables are virtual, you cannot insert data directly into them. For
      example, you cannot run <codeph>atload</codeph> to load a new user into
        <codeph>system.users</codeph>.</p>
      <p>To explore the state of your system, run the <codeph>atview</codeph> command; for more
      information, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-4_4-Examining-the-State-_snsg.xml#topic_4_4"/> and <xref href="c_admin_guide-5_6-Monitoring-an-EDW-In_snsg.xml#topic_5_6"/>.</p>
      <p>To explore authorization and authentication data, run the <codeph>atquery</codeph> command
      against specific system tables.</p>
   </conbody>
</concept>