<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_4_1_5_1">
   <title>Authentication Options</title>
   <conbody>
      <parml>
         <plentry>
            <pt>
               <codeph>--user=&lt;<i>user_name</i>&gt;</codeph>
            </pt>
            <pt>
               <codeph>--user=default</codeph>
            </pt>
            <pd>Runs the command under the authorization of <i>&lt;user_name&gt;</i>, who must be a user
          defined in the EDW instance. If you specify default, the atload command runs under the
          authorization of the user specified by the ADDAMARK_USER environment variable. <note>To
            log in as the <b>guest</b> user, do not specify the <codeph>--pass</codeph> or
              <codeph>--shared-secret</codeph> flags. The default is to run the command under the
            authorization of the currently logged-in user. </note>
            </pd>
         </plentry>
      </parml>
      <parml>
         <plentry>
            <pt>
               <codeph>--pass=&lt;password&gt;</codeph>
            </pt>
            <pt>
               <codeph>--pass=file:&lt;path_and_filename&gt;</codeph>
            </pt>
            <pd>Specifies the password that authenticates the user that you specified with the
            <codeph>--user</codeph> option. You can specify the password in clear text on the
          command line. You can place the password in a file and specify its location and file name
          on the command line. If you omit the <codeph>--pass</codeph> option, the atload command
          uses the password specified by the ADDAMARK_PASSWORD environment variable.</pd>
            <pd>For more information, see <xref href="c_admin_guide-4_1_5_2-Setting-the-ADDAMARK_snsg.xml#topic_4_1_5_2"/>.</pd>
         </plentry>
      </parml>
      <parml>
         <plentry>
            <pt>
               <codeph>--shared-secret=default</codeph>
            </pt>
            <pd>Specifies the shared secret for the hosts in the EDW instance. You can specify the
          shared secret in clear text on the command line. You can place the shared secret in a file
          and specify its location and file name on the command line. If you specify default, the
          atload command uses the shared secret specified by the ADDAMARK_SHARED_SECRET environment
          variable.</pd>
            <pd>The value for <codeph>--pass</codeph> takes precedence over the value for
            <codeph>--shared-secret</codeph> if both are present.</pd>
         </plentry>
      </parml>
      <parml>
         <plentry>
            <pt>
               <codeph>--skip-queues</codeph>
            </pt>
            <pd>Bypasses normal EDW task queueing.</pd>
            <pd>You must specify the <codeph>--shared-secret</codeph> option when you use the
            <codeph>--skip-queues</codeph> option.</pd>
         </plentry>
      </parml>
   </conbody>
</concept>