<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_10_1_1">
   <title>Models for Managing Local Storage Space</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>The default configuration of an EDW instance uses local disk space for its storage space.
      With local storage space, an EDW instance stores and retrieves data very quickly. However, as
      the amount of stored historical data grows, local disk space can run out.</p>
      <p>
         <draft-comment author="Hemraj" translate="no">GET MORE DETAILS ON THIS FROM BUG REPORT
        SS-13516</draft-comment>
      </p>
      <p>
         <note>SenSage AP does not support de-duplicating identical data in a Nearline storage because
        the files are laid out differently on disk.</note>
      </p>
      <p>
         <draft-comment author="Hemraj" translate="no">Please provide more details, maybe a good example can make it
        more understandable.</draft-comment>
      </p>
      <p>The EDW component supports two methods for expanding EDW (Event Data Warehouse Server)
      storage capacity:</p>
      <ul id="ul_cx1_1l4_wx">
         <li>
            <b>Archiving data</b>
            <p>Archiving data requires configuring the EDW component to
          communicate with Nearline storage devices. The EDW then can move old data from local
          storage onto Nearline storage. Old data on local storage is replaced with references to
          its location on Nearline storage. These references let you reclaim local storage space for
          new data, because references to archived data are much smaller than the data
          itself.</p>
            <p>Archiving data allows you to reserve local storage for recent data. Queries
          of recent data execute quickly because the data is on local storage. Historical data
          remains accessible on Nearline storage, but queries execute more slowly. When a person
          queries the EDW for archived data, it automatically and transparently retrieves the data
          regardless of whether it is in local or Nearline storage.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <b>Retiring data</b>
            <p>Retiring data deletes it from the storage space of EDW instances
          and reclaims the storage space that it consumed. After you retire data, it is completely
          gone and is not accessible to queries. Retire data instead of archiving it only if you do
          not need access to the historical data that you retire.</p>
            <note type="important">
          Retiring data from an EDW table removes only data that is not stored under retention on a
          Nearline storage device. The command skips archived data that is under retention and logs
          a message that provides the date in the future when the Nearline storage device will allow
          you to retire the data. That date is the earliest you can retire the data. The command
          does remove archived data that is not under retention or its retention period has passed.
          On some Nearline storage devices, however, in order to ensure retire time specifications
          are enforced, the command may be required to restore some data not under retention and let
          it remain online even though it falls outside the retire date. For more information, see
            <xref href="c_admin_guide-4_5-Retiring-Data_snsg.xml#topic_4_5"/>.</note>
         </li>
      </ul>
   </conbody>
</concept>