<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_7_4_3">
   <title>Tracking Uploads in the EDW</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>In addition to loading log data into the specified tables, <codeph>atload</codeph> saves
      information in the EDW</p>
      <p>about the load. You can view this load information by querying these system tables:</p>
      <ul id="ul_bh1_tyv_vx">
         <li>
            <codeph>system.upload_info</codeph>
            <p>This table enables administrators to check on upload
          status in the system. When the system is healthy, this table returns one row for each
          upload. When the upload data is not consistent across all the nodes in the cluster, this
          table returns a value of <codeph>false</codeph> in the CONSISTENT column. In this case,
          the table may return multiple rows with the same value in the UPLOADID column; all of
          these rows are marked as inconsistent.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <codeph>system.raw_upload_info</codeph>
            <p>This table enables a support person to see the
          raw data that is distributed across the system in order to troubleshoot an inconsistency
          problem revealed in the<codeph> system.upload_info</codeph> data.</p>
         </li>
      </ul>
      <p>Both of these system tables contain a unique identifier for the upload: the value of the
        <codeph>_uploadid</codeph> column. These tables store additional information for each load
      operation, which includes: the minimum and maximum timestamps, the number of lines in the
      source log data, the number of lines successfully parsed by the PTL file, the number of rows
      loaded into the specified EDW table, the PTL file and client signatures, and whether the load
      was successful.</p>
      <p>Additionally, the <codeph>system.upload_info</codeph> table returns the consistency data and
      the <codeph>system.raw_upload_info</codeph> returns the logical name of the source node for
      the log data.</p>
      <p>As it begins loading data into the log tables, the EDW inserts a new row in these system
      tables to track the upload. Initially, the value of the SUCCESSFUL column defaults to
        <codeph>false</codeph>. When the load completes successfully, this column's value changes to
      true.</p>
      <p>IgniteTech recommends that you regularly query the <codeph>system.upload_info</codeph> table
      for loads with inconsistent data (the value of the CONSISTENT column is
      <codeph>false</codeph>). Inconsistent data was not correctly replicated across the cluster.
      Whenever you discover an inconsistent load, query the <codeph>system.raw_upload_info</codeph>
      table and capture the results in a file, contact IgniteTech Support: send email to
      info@ignitetech.com or call +1 800-248-0027.</p>
   </conbody>
</concept>