<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_4_4_3_2">
   <title>Namespace Identification</title>
   <conbody>
      <parml>
         <plentry>
            <pt>
               <codeph>--namespace=&lt;name&gt;</codeph>
            </pt>
            <pd>Identifies the namespace from which to query information. The default is default. To specify
         the top level, use "" (empty quotation marks).
         <p>If you run the <codeph>atview</codeph> command without specifying a table name, the output includes all tables
           in the specified namespace. For example, if you specify <codeph>--namespace=hq.west</codeph>, the command
           returns the requested information for every table in the hq.west namespace.</p>
               <p>If you specify a table when you run the atview command, the output includes the requested
           information only for the specified table. For example, if you specify <codeph>--namespace=hq.west
           columns mytbl</codeph>, the output is specific to <codeph>hq.west.mytbl</codeph>.</p>
               <note>When you run atview, you can specify a table name explicitly (for example,
             ns1.ns2.ns3.mytable) or use the <codeph>--namespace=&lt;namespace&gt;</codeph> flag to specify the namespace.
             When you use the namespace flag, you can specify the namespace once for an entire command;
             SenSage AP prepends the specified namespace to each table name used in the rest of the
             request.</note>
               <p>The command will display an ’error’ column and include error messages in the column when
           there are inconsistencies across hosts in the cluster. For example, error type
           TABLE_OPEN_FAILURE displays in the ’error’ column when the owner of a view is deleted from the
           system and the view no longer carries the permissions associated with the former owner.</p>
            </pd>
         </plentry>
      </parml>
   </conbody>
</concept>