<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_9_3_1">
   <title>Setting up the Analyzer Administration Account</title>
   <conbody>
      <p>In SenSage AP, the AD Administrator can set up an Analyzer administration login account and
      if desired, map that account to a desired user as noted in steps 1 and 2 below.</p>
      <ol>
         <li>Create an enumerator user that will be used to connect to AD/LDAP. This user requires READ- ONLY
        access to view all other AD/LDAP users who will be synchronized with AP Analyzer. <note>By
          default, this enumerator user belongs to the Analyzer “Admin” account. Unlike all other
          AD/LDAP users specified in AP Analyzer, the Analyzer "Admin" user is given full
          administrative rights to AP Analyzer.</note>
            <note type="important">: When issuing a
          username and password for the enumerator user, be sure it is unique and not used by any
          other AD/LDAP user. The enumerator user will be mapped to the Analyzer "Admin" user until
          the mapping is changed.</note>
         </li>
         <li>If you want to designate the Analyzer "Admin" user as the SenSage AP Administrator, create
        an appropriate Active Directory account for the SenSage AP Administrator, for example,
          <b>AdminUser</b>. Then follow these steps: <ol>
               <li>Log into Analyzer and go to <menucascade>
                     <uicontrol>Administration</uicontrol>
                     <uicontrol>Users</uicontrol>
                  </menucascade>. </li>
               <li>Select <b>Admin</b> and click <b>Edit</b>.</li>
               <li>Change the DN mapping in the LDAP/AD Admin DN field to point to the <b>AdminUser</b>
            account in AD.</li>
            </ol>
            <note>The Analyzer "Admin" can only be mapped to an AD SAM account name. The system
          will make the necessary changes to the Analyzer "Admin" account (default is "Admin") so
          that the username of the Analyzer "Admin" user becomes the SAM account name of the entered
          DN.</note>
            <p>The Analyzer "Admin" will now be able to log into SenSage AP Analyzer with his or her own
          AD credentials with the username as the SAM Account name and the password the same as the
          one used in AD/LDAP.</p>
            <fig>
               <title> Mapping Analyzer Admin to another Administrator Account</title>
               <image href="./media/Image_259.jpg" placement="break" id="image_jlz_nzn_wx"/>
            </fig>
         </li>
      </ol>
   </conbody>
</concept>