<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_1_4">
   <title>Conventions Used in SenSage AP Documentation</title>
   <conbody>
    <table id="table_ojw_bf4_yx">
      <tgroup cols="3">
        <colspec colnum="1" colname="c1" colwidth="1*"/>
        <colspec colnum="2" colname="c2" colwidth="3.28*"/>
        <colspec colnum="3" colname="c3" colwidth="2.38*"/>
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry>This convention...</entry>
            <entry>Indicates...</entry>
            <entry>Example</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><b>bold text</b></entry>
            <entry>Names of user interface items, such as field names, buttons, menu choices, and
              keystrokes</entry>
            <entry>Click <b>Clear Filter</b>.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><i>italic text</i></entry>
            <entry>Indicates a variable name or a new term the first time it appears</entry>
            <entry>
              <p>http://&lt;<i>host</i>>:&lt;<i>port</i>>/ index.mhtml</p>
              <p>Use the whammerjammer to adjust the whamming frequency.</p>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><codeph>Courier text</codeph></entry>
            <entry>Indicates a literal value, such as a command name, file name, information typed
              by the user, or information displayed by the system</entry>
            <entry>atquery localhost:8072 myquery.sql</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>CAPS</entry>
            <entry>Indicates a key on the computer keyboard</entry>
            <entry>Press ENTER.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>{ }</entry>
            <entry>
              <p>In a syntax line, curly braces surround a set of options from which you must choose
                one and only one.</p>
              <p>NOTE: Syntax specifications for SELECT statements include curly braces as part of
                the {INCLUDE_BAD_LOADS] keyword.</p>
            </entry>
            <entry>{ start | stop | restart }</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>[ ]</entry>
            <entry>In a syntax line, square brackets surround an optional parameter</entry>
            <entry>
              <p>atquery [options]</p>
              <p>&lt;<i>host</i>>:&lt;<i>port</i>> -</p>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>|</entry>
            <entry>In a syntax line, a pipe within square brackets or curly braces separates a
              choice between mutually exclusive parameters NOTE: Syntax for defining a Nearline
              Storage Address (NSA) includes a pipe.</entry>
            <entry>{ start | stop | restart } [g|m]</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>...</entry>
            <entry>In a syntax line, ellipses indicate a repetition of the previous
              parameter</entry>
            <entry>
              <p>The following example indicates you can enter multiple, comma-separated
                options:</p>
              <p>&lt;<i>option</i>>[, &lt;<i>option</i>>[…]]</p>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>backslash (\)</entry>
            <entry>A backslash in command-line syntax or in a command example behaves as the escape
              character on Unix. It removes any special meaning from the character immediately
              following it. In SenSage AP documentation, a backslash nullifies the special meaning
              of the newline character as a command terminator. Without the backslash, pressing
              ENTER at the end of the line causes the Unix system to execute the text preceding the
              ENTER. Without the backslash, you must allow long commands to wrap over multiple lines
              as a single line.</entry>
            <entry>
              <p>atquery --user=administrator \</p>
              <p>--pass=pass:p@ss localhost:8072\</p>
              <p>-e='SELECT * FROM</p>
              <p>system.users;'</p>
            </entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </conbody>
</concept>
