<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" id="topic_1_2">
   <title>SenSage AP Analyzer Guide Organization</title>
   <conbody>
    <p>This book contains the following chapters:</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-2-GETTINGSTARTED_crm.xml"/>—Describes Analyzer basics to get started,
      including an introduction to the system, how to login, use its menus and interface, navigate
      between subcomponents, and perform timezone and access configuration.</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-3-VIEWINGREPORTS-CHA_crm.xml"/>—Describes describes how to use SenSage
      AP Analyzer to view and filter reports and charts, and display data models.</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-4-CREATING-ANDMODIFYI_crm.xml"/>—Describes how to create an initial,
      default dashboard, add dashboards, modify them, and use their features.</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-5-CREATING-MODIFYING_crm.xml"/>—Describes how to use the Analyzer
      Report Creation Wizard to create a basic report along with optional configuration features
      such as runtime parameters, complex data filters, and integration with data models.</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-6-CREATING-ANDMODIFYI_crm.xml"/>—Describes how to use SenSage AP
      Analyzer to create and modify a chart corresponding to a report.</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-7-USINGANALYTICSWORK_crm.xml"/>—Describes how to use SenSage AP Data
      Analytics Workbench, interactive and visual Data Modeling tool, to create, alter, and execute
      data models.</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-8-USINGSQL-WORKBENCH-_crm.xml"/>—Describes how to use the Analyzer’s
      Data Analytics Workbench, interactive and visual Data Modeling tool, to create, alter, and
      execute data models.</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-9-MANAGINGREPORT-AND_crm.xml"/>—Describes how to manage report and
      analytics schedules through the Analyzer’s Scheduler, where users can create report schedules
      and view the output of scheduled reports.</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-10-ADMINISTERINGSENSAG_crm.xml"/>—Describes how to use SenSage AP
      Analyzer to administer SenSage AP users, including maintenance of their assigned roles and
      groups.</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-11-USINGIMPORT-EXPORT_crm.xml"/>—</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-12-ADMINISTERINGDATAM_crm.xml"/>—</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-13-APPENDIXA-NAMESPAC_crm.xml"/>—Contains both the SenSage AP version
      5.x.x and 6.x.x procedure to limit a user’s access to a namespace(s).</p>
    <p><xref href="c_sen_anal-14-APPENDIXB-SENSAGE_crm.xml"/>—Lists role privileges and permissions
      that are required to perform specific actions (such as view, edit, run, delete, etc) in each
      feature of the SenSage AP application (reporting, scheduling, etc).</p>
  </conbody>
</concept>